Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hello, good evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to the Ask
Abij show. This is episode 347
and we are going to discuss whatever is
happening in the world right now.
Whatever you want to discuss, but we
we're going to focus a little bit
specifically on what's happening in Iran
and a lot is happening in Iran, right?
The Iran war, the war that the US and
Israel have launched upon Iran. There
was a ceasefire
and uh what's going on in the ceasefire.
So, we're going to discuss that. But let
me see before we start any of that let's
see who all is there on the live stream
on the live chat. Uh who do we have? We
have Lavish Lovish Tindil Sarkcar Bhavy
Gupta uh Retita Retita Salatia Retita
Salatia
Nan Nilan Nilan Jan Go Nanjen Gosh.
Okay. as Niling Goo and
Ritik Pawar uh Tapishi Tapishi Karthik
Karthik is here
KR Singh Man teaching tricks manha
geopolitical way from Indor good evening
sir Anurva Ashwani Sharma Anurva once
again Rohani Bahad Dan Patel Bonjour
really love Miss Patel Kushal Mangal Yes
ma'am. Uh DI Shrian Arvind Kr Singh
wonderful evening indeed. Alkashukari
namaste Tuhin Ray uh Tanesh Pande Anoj
Dikshit Sharat Menan Ishwar 8457 Nirvana
Shanks A
um
Hitchhiker's Guide Good to see you third
volume started excellent good excellent
uh excellent book. Uh Dvik Shrian
Samraat Shukla Tanesh Pandi Mahul Rajes
Babu Cintillating Kids Pratt Namaste G
Samra Chukla Gru 75 Aush Singh Good
evening Ran Hapana good to see you Ran
Hapana Samra Chukla Honey Badger of
Kolinga good to see you
Danush Nanesh Samra Chukla um Swami is
here from Jaipur Navit Samanik
Ankush Sharma photography
Um who else we have? PG Deutsland. Hello
from Deutschand. Hello to Deutsland. Uh
Dad Panchal Panchi Sudanha
Sur Suresh Sibatch. Hello watching from
Ireland. Well good to have you. Good
evening I suppose in Ireland. Yes. Kahan
is here from Sakit New Delhi. Fanloop is
here. Ashwameda from great Nikobar
Island. Fantastic. Outstanding. Brave
robot Dak Si from Jaipur. Kumar Xi she
Trump
um Sagav Marshall Si and Brown
Leprechaun again from Ireland. Um
Cosmic Lab is here from Rome Rome in
Italy. Yes, Italy. Hi Penguin is here
from Kathmandu. Good to see you Heni
Penguin again. Wise idiot.
Ashish Chabra
um Kahan Manhattan I6W pain to see ready
always ready present present good to
have you
wenesh from Bangalore Kapil Singh from
Uttarakhan Rashi Kudin uh Jayant from
Berlin Vinay from Azamgar Mlevin once
again and everybody else okay so I won't
be able to greet you all individually
but thank you so much for being on this
live stream now let's discuss what's
happening what's
the these days things are moving so fast
in this war the war that's been launched
against Iran you know things are
happening so fast that um
if I do a live stream after 3 days it's
like half the half the world has been
you know things have I mean that failed
American attempt to steal Iranian
uranium it's now it it now seems like
old history even though it happened less
than a week ago
The Americans tried to steal. They sent
multiple large transport planes and
multiple helicopters and god knows so
much more. And they they they tried they
landed in Iran on a makeshift airstrip
and they tried to steal uranium from
Iran and the whole operation turned uh
ended up being a complete disaster. They
lost they lost about 12 aircraft in the
process and then they declared victory
that you know what we were able to
extract that one pilot that was missing.
The pilot was missing 200 km away. So
that's old news now. It it happened just
five five or so days ago. That's old
news now. Now yesterday what happened is
that a ceasefire was announced and then
everything the ceasefire has collapsed.
So let's quickly recap from Twitter
what's happened in the past uh past day
or so, right?
Um okay. So here we have this tweet um
this this post by Shahbas Sharif. This
is from of course yesterday. He says,
"Diplomatic efforts for peaceful
settlement of the ongoing war in the
Middle East are progressing steadily,
strongly and powerfully with the
potential to lead to substantive results
in the near future to allow diplomacy to
run its course. I earnestly request the
great magnificent
uh Dyur Mahapur President Trump to
extend the deadline for two weeks.
Pakistan in all sincerity requests
Iranian brothers Iranian brothers to
open the state of Hormuz for a
corresponding period of two weeks as a
goodwill gesture. We also urge all
waring parties to observe a ceasefire
everywhere for two weeks to allow
diplomacy to to achieve conclusive
termination of war in the interest of
long-term peace and stability of the
region.
This is what Mr. Sharif tweeted and then
this this came out. So Sharif initially
okay Sharif is the so-called prime
minister of Pakistan. He has never been
elected but he's the prime minister. So
it emerged that this guy Sharif had
actually uh posted the the the message
as a draft earlier. So it it was titled
draft Pakistan prime minister's message
on X and then the whole thing was copy
pasted for him. So he or whoever is
running his account copy pasted the
entire thing including the title draft
Pakistan's prime minister message on X.
Now if Shabbah Sharif's interns or
employees would have drafted the message
for him, they would have said that this
is the prime minister's message on X,
not the Pakistan's prime minister
message on X. So clearly this this this
draft came in from somewhere of outside
of Pakistan. Right? It came from
somewhere outside of Pakistan. Someone
one of his masters probably in
Washington or something, they drafted
this for him and they asked him to post
this. So then he edited the message and
uh that is this message that we see
here. So it was given to him by one of
his masters whoever is handling him
probably from from Washington DC maybe
some other u some other national capital
maybe not far from here maybe but
definitely not.
So uh Sharif is essentially a message
boy an errand boy. Okay. So uh this
happened and then after after some time
okay a few hours later he tweeted this.
Shabbaz Sharif with the greatest
humility I am pleased to announce that
the Islamic Republic of Iran and the
United States of America along with
their allies have agreed to an immediate
ceasefire everywhere including Lebanon
including Lebanon and elsewhere
effective immediately. I warmly welcome
the sagacious gesture and extend deepest
gratitude to the leadership of both the
countries and invite their delegations
to Islamabad on Friday 10th of April
which is tomorrow to further negotiate
for a conclusive agreement to settle all
disputes. Both parties have displayed
blah blah blah remarkable wisdom and
understanding and all that. We earnestly
hope that the Islamavad talks succeed in
achieving sustainable peace and wish to
share more good news in the coming days.
and he has tagged uh Trump who is his
boss, JD Vance who is his vice boss and
all his other bosses. He's also tagged
Dr. Peskan Pijkan the uh president of
Iran and uh and so on. Okay, so this is
what happened
then um this came out. Okay, this came
out yesterday once again. Uh this is a
message by Trump by by the American
president Mr. Trump. The United States
will work closely with Iran, which we
have determined has gone through what
will be a productive regime change, a
very productive regime change. So,
according to Trump, there's been a
regime change in in Iran. And he says
there will be no enrichment of uranium.
The United States will working with Iran
dig up and remove all of the deeply
buried uh nuclear dust. It is now and
has been under very exacting satellite
surveillance. Nothing has been touched
from the date of attack from last year
when when Trump had attacked these these
Natans and for sites. Uh we are and will
be talking uh tariff tariff and
sanctions relief with Iran. Many of the
15 points have already been agreed to.
That's what Trump claimed yesterday. Now
this was uh the this is the white house
official account and they tweeted this
on Twitter uh the official statement of
Iran. So Iran says on behalf of the
Islamic Republic of Iran, I express the
gratit I express gratitude and
appreciation for my dear brothers the
prime minister of Pakistan Sharif and
Field Marshall Munir for their
incredibly tireless efforts to end the
war in the region in response to the
brotherly request of Prime Minister
Sharif in his tweet and considering the
request by the US for negotiations based
on the American 15-point proposal as
well as announcement by the president of
US about acceptance of the general
framework of Iran's 10-point proposal.
As a basis for negotiations, I hereby
declare on behalf of Iran's Supreme
National Security Council, if attacks
against Iran are halted, our powerful
armed forces are tweeting like Trump
will seize their defensive operations
for a period of two weeks. A safe
passage through the state of Hormuz will
be possible via coordination with Iran's
armed forces and with due consideration
of technical limitations and signed by
Sayyad Abbas Aragi, the minister of
foreign affairs, Islamic Republic of
Iran. So this is something the white
house officially acknowledged that this
is this is what Iran has uh stated
officially.
Then
Trump also made this statement based on
conversations with Prime Minister
Shabbaz Sharif and Field Marshall
Marshall Aim Munir of Pakistan and
wherein they requested that I hold off
the destructive force being sent tonight
to Iran and subject to the Islamic
Republic of Iran agreeing to the
complete complete immediate and safe
opening of the state of Hormuz. I agree
to suspend the bombing in Iran attack on
Iran of Iran for a period of two weeks.
This will be a double-sided ceasefire.
Trump says the reason for doing so is
that we have already met. We have
already met our beautiful military
objectives. We have already exceeded all
our beautiful big beautiful brilliant
military objectives and are very far
along with a definitive agreement
concerning long-term peace with Iran and
peace in the Middle East. We received a
10-point proposal from Iran and believe
it's a workable basis on which to
negotiate. So Trump says that we've
received the 10-point proposal from Iran
and we believe it's a workable basis on
which to negotiate. Almost all of the
various points of past contention have
been agreed to between the US and Iran
uh by a twoe period uh but the twoe
period will allow agreement the
agreement to be finalized and
consummated. consummated. Okay,
consummated if you say so on behalf of
the US of America as president and blah
blah blah all that okay so Trump says
that it's it's uh an honor to have this
long-term problem close to resolution
okay so thus far things are going fine
and then the white house tweets tweets
this okay uh god knows how many yeah
this these are the white house's claims
these are the American claims of what
they've achieved in operation epic fury
then Israel tweets this Israel defense
forces okay they tweeted said this
yesterday afternoon India time uh 1:39
p.m. India time in accordance with
directives from the political echelon
the Israel Defense Forces IDF has seized
fire in the operation against Iran and
is highly prepared to respond decisively
against any violation. Overnight, the
IDF conducted a widecale wave of strikes
targeting missile launch sites and
launches across Iran in order to
significantly degrade Iran's launching
capabilities simultaneously and this is
interesting. Simultaneously in Lebanon,
the IDF is continuing to target to
conduct targeted ground operations
against the IDF will continue to operate
across all fronts to defend Israel. So
they are saying that simultaneously in
Lebanon in Lebanon they are continuing
to conduct targeted ground operations
against Hezbollah. Now Shabbash Sharif
says the ceasefire includes Lebanon.
Okay. And Israel says we are now
targeting Lebanon. We are simultaneously
targeting Lebanon. So what kind of
operations did is was Israel doing
yesterday against Lebanon. So this is a
claim from by someone from Lebanon.
Okay. I don't know if it's true or not,
but a lot of similar claims have come
out. So this lady, whoever she is, she
says that I don't think people around
the world realize how bad the attack on
Lebanon was today. Okay, it's bad. Like
911 bad. Hospitals are overflowing and
do not have enough blood. We still don't
know what the death toll is. This is
terrorism allegedly, pure and simple.
April 8, never forget. So it looks like
Israel did very massive air strikes and
other operations on u on on Lebanon
Beirut also right and looks like a lot
of civilians may possibly have died
allegedly. I don't know how true or not
it is but this is what it this is what a
lot of people from that place Lebanon
are saying.
Then this is what Iran said. Okay, this
is the Iranian u uh embassy's account
from from India and they say that you
started the war but Iran set the
conditions for its end and this these
are the 10 points. Okay, this is the
Iranian 10point proposal that was
accepted by Trump as a as a workable
basis for for negotiations. So Iran's
10-point conditions that the US has
accepted as workable say u that the and
and the US has fundamentally committed
to non-aggression continuation of Iran's
control of the state of Hormos
acceptance of Iran's uranium enrichment
lifting all primary sanctions lifting
all secondary sanctions termination of
all UN security council resolutions
termination of all IAEA board of
governors resolutions payment of
compensation to Iran withdrawal of US
combat forces in the region from the
region and secession of war on all
fronts including against the heroic
Islamic resistance of Lebanon and where
is it? Trump said that we received a
10-point proposal and believe it's a
workable basis on which to negotiate. So
Trump said it's fine. We can negotiate
bas based on these 10 points these 10
points including secession of war on all
fronts including against Lebanon
uh you know continuation of Iran's
control over the state of Hormuz u uh
acceptance of Iran's enrichment of
uranium and so on. So Trump said it's
fine. We can negotiate on the basis of
these 10 points. It's it's it's a
workable um you know set of conditions.
Then what happens then it look then okay
this is still we don't know if it's true
or not but it looks like this is what
happened. This is yesterday once again
in the afternoon. It's now confirmed
that the UAE air force UAE air force has
conducted a large scale operation
targeting Iran's oil and petrochemical
plants plants in the Persian Gulf
region. They have bombed refineries on
the islands of Siri and Lavan and
targeted multiple other petrochemical
facilities using not only Winglong 2
armed for armed drones but also Mirage
2000 EAD fighter jets. operations are in
ongoing with reports that Emirati
aircraft have also flown over for the
southern Iran.
Now, this is incredibly perplexing. Why
would the UAE do this? I'm not sure if
it's confirmed or not that the UAE did
this, but what on earth? So, clearly
there was action going on against Iran
yesterday.
Now, there's there's more.
Um, this is u Trump considering a plan
to punish. So the the thing is
yesterday there were attacks against
Iran. There were there were uh let me
see what else do we have
there. There were explosions in Thran.
There were strikes on Iran's uh oil
facilities. Okay. Petrochemical
facilities yesterday. The war that
Israel has launched against Lebanon is
continuing. It's they they're doing very
heavy bombing uh you know bombing
operations over Lebanon on Beirut and
Iran says that this is not a ceasefire.
I mean you are not uh adhering to the
the the what we had agreed upon as part
the terms that we had agreed to for the
ceasefire. So what's happened is that
Iran has now once again closed the state
of Hormos. So the ceasefire essentially
has collapsed. Is it retrievable or not
is the question. So let's before we
analyze this, let's let's move forward.
Trump is considering a plan to punish
some NATO countries by moving US troops
out of countries which are deemed
unhelpful to the Iran war. The proposal
would involve moving US troops from
unhelpful countries into countries that
were more supportive of the Iran war. Um
it's going on. They're discussing how to
NAT how to punish NATO. The US has
84,000 troops roughly stationed across
Europe and countries that could benefit
from more American troops. Yeah, that's
benefit. Um include Poland, Romania,
Lithuania, and Greece and US NATO
relations are degrading.
Um this is another tweet by Trump
yesterday.
um all American ships, aircraft, and
military personnel with additional
ammunition, weaponry, and anything else
that's appropriate and necessary for the
lethal prosecution and destruction of an
already substantially degraded enemy
will remain in place in and around Iran
until such time as the real agreement
reached is fully complied with. If for
reason it is not, which is highly
unlikely, then the shooting stars starts
bigger and better and stronger than
anyone has ever seen before. It was
agreed a long time ago and despite all
of the fake rhetoric to the country, no
nuclear weapons. No nuclear weapons. So
Trump uh where here he says that we are
fine with the 10point proposal that Iran
has given and the 10-point proposal
included enrichment uranium enrichment
by Iran. Okay, that was a workable basis
for negotiations said Trump. And now he
says that u no nuclear weapons which
means no enrichment right and the
straight for straight of hormones will
be open and safe. So Trump is saying
that we and and what else do we have um
withdrawal of US combat forces from the
region is one of the points that Iran
had uh put forth and Trump said it's
fine and now he is saying that you know
what we are not withdrawing anything we
are moving in more forces. We are
potentially moving in more forces into
the Gulf region. Yep. Russian Gulf
region. America is back. So, looks like
very rapidly the ceasefire started
unraveling.
Uh, now we have this. Okay, now we have
this. Okay, it's muted. Boop boop.
Okay, so this is from today more today
afternoon massive American buildup. The
this is from Reuters. The US has now
deployed more than 50,000 troops across
the Middle East with numbers continuing
to surge. Thousands of Marines are being
rapidly transferred from San Diego right
straight into the region. Anyone who
thinks that President Trump sent this
entire Armada fleets, Marines and all
just to accept a truce with Iran is
completely delusional. a fullscale
ground intervention ground
this ceasefire this two week ceasefire
as a means to bolster their presence in
the region and then they will carry out
further attacks it looks like on Iran
and Trump has given Europe an ultimatum
within days they must commit actual
military forces like warships to the
straight of Hormos this is being
reported by their spiggel the kegel
Germany.
So that's what's going on. That is
what's happening.
Okay. Now I
So essentially what's what what is the
deal? Two week ceasefire. It's already
collapsing. Okay. The Israelis have
ensured it collapses. The deal the
ceasefire deal the points the 10 points
it included
that there'll be it included Lebanon.
there will be no no military action on
Lebanon. Karif tweeted that Iran said
that and now immediately Israel
yesterday started really going hard on
Lebanon and they seem to have caused a
lot of casualties among civilians
possibly potentially allegedly.
So Israel ensured that the ceasefire
collapses
and looks like the UAE did some military
action against Iran and there were
explosions in Thran yesterday.
So Iran has closed the state of Hormos
and now you know Trump is saying that
Iran is not holding or you know it's
it's not uh being true to its
commitments as for the ceasefire and so
on. So the ceasefire is collapsing. Now
what actually happened? How did this
entire the whole thing go wrong? Iran
gave a 10-point proposal. The United
States has a 15-point proposal. The U
the US president said that the 10 points
Iran has given are workable workable
basis for negotiations.
Then he said that no we never knew that
you know Lebanon was not included.
Leberon was not included in the 10
points. That's what he claims. And then
JD Vance the American vice president
said that there seems to be a genuine
misunderstanding. What they communicated
is not what we received. That's what he
claims. Now who is the intermediary in
all of this? It's Pakistan.
Pakistan is the intermediary in this
entire matter. Pakistan is the mediator.
See, Iran says we will not speak to the
United States face to face. They are
aggressors. We don't want to negotiate
with them. But if Pakistan wants to
mediate, okay, we will deal with
Pakistan. So Pakistan has been the
intermediary. They have spoken to the US
because the US is their master
and they've spoken to Iran because they
are a neighbor of Iran temporarily at
least.
So they are the intermediary and they
have spoken to both sides but both sides
haven't spoken to each other. So both
sides have spoken to Pakistan. So looks
like one of two things has happened.
Scenario one we'll keep it here on this
side. Scenario one. Scenario one is
Pakistan gave a s certain
made Pakistan made a certain set of set
of statements to Iran and a totally
different set of statements to the US.
So it said one thing to Iran and said a
different thing to the US and that has
caused the complete devastating
misunderstanding if it's a
misunderstanding which means that
Pakistan has essentially
um
botched up the whole thing. Pakistan has
lied to both sides essentially.
That's one scenario that Pakistan has
its own agenda. It is playing its own
game. They lied to Iran about what the
American proposal was and they lied to
the US what the Iran Iranian proposal
was. They said two different things to
two different sides and that's why
there's a fundamental mismatch and
that's why the ceasefire has collapsed.
That's one scenario of this scenario
here. The second scenario here is that
the Pakistanis are simply obeying
American orders.
The Americans told Pakistan to go ahead
and mediate and all that and you take
the Iranian proposal give it to us and
we will claim that we have never agreed
to this even though we have put out all
these tweets. So in that case Pakistan
has played the role of a faithful
servant
of the master the United States and in
both scenarios Pakistan has backstabbed
betrayed Iran.
Right? That is what's going on.
So yesterday a whole bunch of Indian
commentators were saying that Pakistan
has become this great great power in
so-called South Asia. They have
leapfrogged India. They are so relevant
now. They can mediate and get get the
war to end. But the truth is that
Pakistan has played the role of a
backstabber and betrayer against Iran.
That's the role Pakistan has played.
Okay? And this has led to a complete
collapse of Pakistan's image and
standing worldwide.
If you see Iranian Twitter, Persian
Twitter, see right now there's a
internet blackout in Iran. Like there is
a blackout in various parts of the Gulf
region. Okay, there's a lot of
censorship. In Iran, there seems to be a
complete blackout. In Israel also you're
not allowed to post images of the you
know uh of the devastation that that has
is happening in Iran. in Israel in the
UE also you're not allowed to post
images and videos of know you know
whatever has happened there so there's
censorship across the place and there
seems to be an internet blackout in in
Iran but there's a big Iranian diaspora
outside of Iran and many of them don't
like the regime of the moolas and
Ayatollas but they still support their
country so if you see the tweets coming
out from the Iranian diaspora they are
in one voice
condemning and essentially
abusing Pakistan right now. It's it's a
it's an interesting phenomenon that that
you can see on Twitter right now. The
whole of Iran is is joining together to
to condemn and abuse Pakistan.
So Pakistan has somehow found a way to
bring India and Iran together the people
of India and Iran together at least. So
that's what's happening. So Pakistan has
played the role of of a mercenary of of
of a backstabber of a betrayer of Iran
and uh it looks like the ceasefire is no
longer holding now I don't know if the
missiles and drones are are flying again
uh but it looks like even if the
ceasefire holds hypothetically okay even
if the ceasefire holds hypothetically
what happens uh so let me bring in my
tweets from which I tweeted yesterday
and uh give me a second. Okay, I'll put
that on the screen.
So, why why has the US agreed to a
ceasefire? The US
Give me a second. So, here we have it.
Um
yeah, here. So, so I said that the war's
current outcome, a USIra tactical
victory and a Iranian strategic victory
has be became irreversible at the point
where fresh reserves or resupplies could
no longer turn the scale. The US and
Israel now have two weeks if the
ceasefire holds for two weeks, they have
two weeks now to move in enough reserves
and resupplies to tip the scale and then
go for the kill against Iran. and Iran
is in is in no position to press in new
reserves or resupplies unless Russia or
China or both step in which is highly
uncertain.
So unless Russia or China or both step
in, Iran has two weeks left to establish
deterance by demonstrably testing the
one weapon that can guarantee its
long-term survival.
And what's that one weapon? I think you
all understand what that one one weapon
is, right?
Um and the US air bridge to the Middle
East continues. The US is still even
though the ceasefire is going on
allegedly at that time it was going on
at least the US is still bringing in new
supplies, new troops etc to the Middle
East. So something is not right the
ceasefire is simply a means of buying
time by the United States and uh then
you have all this happening. Israel has
born Beirut in a devastating attack that
could have caused hundreds of casualties
potentially says Alzer. So the ceasefire
was hanging by a thread and I don't know
if it still exists or not the ceasefire.
So that's the day that's what's happened
thus far in the past day day and a half
right.
So even if the ceasefire holds the US is
bringing in more troops the US is
bringing in more equipment more supplies
more whatever else.
If if you're serious about a ceasefire
you don't do that. Right. And one of the
one of the conditions Iran has given is
that the US must move out its military
etc from the from the Gulf region. The
US is doing the opposite of that. So
this ceasefire is not viable and the
longer Iran waits you know the more uh
disadvantageous its position becomes
actually.
So this is so this war is not over. This
ceasefire may in the be the process of
collapsing. It may have collapsed
already. Even if it holds for 2 weeks,
the US is not going to agree to Iran's
conditions of uh continuing its
enrichment of uranium for whatever
reason.
And Iran's trump card is its hold over
the state of Hormos. If it gives that
up, well, what does it have? So the US
will bring in more reserves, more
supplies, more arms, ammunition,
rockets,
missiles, whatnot. And I think in a in a
couple of weeks at most or maybe
whatever the time is, I think the war is
going to resume. This is not over by any
stretch of the imagination.
Okay. So now let's take some questions
from you all. What questions do we have?
All right. We have a question by Ritik
Pawar. Despite having larger economies
and military power, why don't China or
India invade at least one oil rich
country to secure oil resources for
themselves?
Because the oil rich countries are under
American protection except for Iran
which is under American attack and still
America can't defeat Iran. So you think
if America and Israel combined can't
defeat Iran, do you think India or China
can defeat Iran? And does India even
want to attack Iran? For what reason
would we attack Iran? In 3,000 years of
history, we have never attacked Iran.
Why would we attack Iran? Are we crazy
or what?
And when it comes to attacking
hypothetically
some of the Persian Gulf countries, they
are under American protection, you
attack them, you come under full under
the full spectrum of American um you
know offensive measures. It's madness to
do that madness.
Okay. Uh the PI core says, "I have great
respect for your initiative, but your
dismissal of feminism as propaganda was
hurtful. Unequal distribution of labor
and safety threat is lived reality for
women.
My dismissal of feminism is propaganda.
No, feminism, I've never said feminism
is propaganda. Feminism, you see,
understand this. Feminism emerged out of
the United States in the 19th century.
It was much needed
in the United States of the 19th
century. Women were secondass,
essentially third class citizens. They
had no right to property. They forget
about rights to the right to vote.
Forget about the right to vote. They did
not even have the right to property.
They were non-persons.
They were essentially non-persons. They
had no recourse to legal legal aid or
whatever the hell. Women were were
deeply deeply oppressed in 19th century
United States and and 18th century in
17th century United States whatever
whatever the US was born in 1776 or
whatever it was right that's in the 18th
century and women were deeply oppressed.
So it was necessary for a movement to
uplift women
to come into existence and that's how
you have the rise and the the the
genesis of feminism in the United States
and feminism was kind of in alliance
with the civil rights movement in the
US. Okay. So understand feminism was
very necessary in a place like the
United States in a deeply oppressive in
inegitarian
unequal society
like the United States and also Europe.
The same was the case in Europe as well
around that time. I mean since the
Christianization of Europe it's been
like that right? So it was necessary for
feminism to emerge and strive to give
women the same rights as men. It was
very important and they achieved that
eventually. Women, you know,
women got the right to vote. Women
eventually acquired the right to
property whenever it happened probably
in the 20th century. So those things
were necessary. Feminism was necessary.
Then what happens is 1950s and 60s
onwards feminism got hijacked
by the Marxists.
Okay, by the leftists.
The leftists eventually hijacked a lot
of these movements that were originally
uh very important that were created for
very good reasons. So then feminism
transmogrified into something totally
different. It transformed,
it morphed into
a tool for dividing society.
Once women get equal rights as men, once
once women get, you know, equal salaries
as men, yeah,
once women get the right to pro
property, the right to vote, all of
those things, most of feminism's job was
done. But no, you got to go forward now.
And Marxism, it always seeks tools to
divide society.
So it's it took over feminism. It
hijacked feminism. The Marxists slowly
gradually infiltrated the feminists
feminist scene and they became the voice
of feminism.
Essentially they hijacked it and then
they start using the same ideas for
dividing society for say that women
should not be content with equal rights.
Now women should take over society. And
if you look at the United States today,
men are oppressed today. Okay? Men are
oppressed. The US, you could say, has is
becoming in more and more of a
gyocentric society.
Now, feminism is about putting men down,
oppressing men, and essentially women
want to become men now biologically. And
that's led to all these weird
manifestations of god knows what in the
United States like transgenderism and uh
physical mutilation of of children and
god knows what else. Okay. So it's not
propaganda. Feminism arose for a very
good reason in that part of the world
where it was required. You understand?
Now distribution of labor and safety
threat. Safety threat. That's why we
have families.
Okay. That's why we have families. And
in some cultures, there's always going
to be a threat to the to women's safety.
In those cultures, well, please send
your feminism there.
Please send feminism there.
Right? But it's not the case in all
societies, in all cultures. There are
cultures where women
have the highest of respect.
For example, Indian civilization, we
always had the highest of respect for
women. Women's rights were enshrined in
everything. In the Art Shastra, for
example, right? in in dharma women's
rights are enshrined and women and men
they are complimentary to each other in
Indian culture right the rules yeah
there are gender rules in Indian culture
you don't like that well please go
somewhere else but there's no gender
rules maybe you could go to the US
but all cultures are distinct and unique
and you've got to respect all cultures
you don't like a certain culture please
go move elsewhere please move to the
Middle East perhaps maybe that's more
egalitarian for you and so on. So there
are safety threats in some cultures,
unequal distribution. Well, why don't
you become a lumberjack if you're a
lady? Would you like to do that? Become
a lumberjack.
Why don't women want equality of of
labor? Why don't 50% of women I mean why
why don't we have women equally
represented as as lumberjacks or in oil
rigs,
right? Because there is a difference in
the physique of men and women. It's a
biological fact whether you like it or
not. There are certain jobs in the labor
in which fall under the category of
labor that women simply can't do
because of their physical limitations
that are simply a consequence and a
factor of biology.
So please understand let's think of
things think about things let's analyze
these things logically rationally
keeping emotions aside
okay I have never said that feminism has
to be dismissed and should be dismissed
feminism
was necessary in the west in the United
States now now superimposing feminism on
societies where it has no relevance I
don't think it's the right thing to do
for example I don't agree that feminism
has any relevance in India.
Feminism has relevance where women are
canonically oppressed,
subjugated, relegated to third class
citizen status. It's never been the case
in India. So there's no need for
feminism in India. Right? So understand
the the whole discussion is nuanced.
It's complex. Feminism has great
relevance in some parts of the world or
it had great relevance in some parts of
the world. But then it's been weaponized
in those parts of the world
and so on. So it's a complex nuanced
discussion. All right. Please don't feel
hurt by this. Think if you find if you
come across some ideas that go against
what you believe. Well, you could you
can choose to have an emotional reaction
to it which is getting hurt or you can
choose to think about it. I know
thinking is hard. It's hard for all of
us. Thinking is hard. It's hard work.
But if you think it through, then you
will grow and become a more mature
person eventually. So that's what I
would say. Please, please look into what
I'm saying. Think about it. Look into
the history of feminism.
Okay? read read a book or two about the
actual history the genesis the origins
of feminism why it emerged where it
emerged
and then see how it's transformed over
the 1950s60s7s onwards
and what what it's done to the United
States and western society etc all right
tapish k thank you so much ma'am thank
you
karthik uh keti thank you very much
karthik gene okay but says I live in the
United States and no one knows about
Pakistan's role in the ceasefire.
It's okay. Yeah. Um Pakistan is not an
important nation. They have not really
played any actual role in the ceasefire.
They have played the role of a spoiler.
They've played the role of a
backslabber. And in the United States,
no one cares anyway about Pakistan,
right? Pakistan is simply an errand boy,
okay, for the United States.
It's simply one of the minions you can
that exist that that that exists at your
beck and call and who exist to serve you
in some way or the other. Right? So
right so over here in India there's been
a whole bunch of people the usual
suspects who have been lording Pakistan
and saying you know Pakistan has become
more relevant than India and so on.
That's what they were doing yesterday.
Today I suppose they must be quiet about
this. Right. Push says like you
previously said that in the past NATO
nations went with the US everywhere
because the previous US administration
considered them to be equals and now
they are not siding with the US because
this um US administration is treating
them like third world nations. So if the
NATO nations of Assad then why do they
need respect from Washington to obey
their orders this time? Love from Bihar.
Um
if the NATO so let's
yeah in the past NATO nations went with
the US they did not go with the US
everywhere they
um they agreed with the United States
and its geopolitical uh agenda and
decisions and they participated in
various US geopolitical initiatives.
which means wars and whatn not sanctions
etc. The NATO nations have done that in
the past and the deal was that the
United States gets to control Europe
physically by putting ground by putting
troops on the ground boots on the ground
in various NATO nations. Okay. And the
US finances a substantial amount of
NATO's military budget all of that. And
in exchange the US gets the privilege of
essentially controlling physically the
the whole of Western Europe. That was
the deal. There was a there was the
unspoken contract
in NATO.
So the NATO nations give up a
significant amount of their sovereignty
to the US. In exchange they get all
these things. So both sides benefit.
That was a win-win. And the US they did
not consider NATO nations to be their
equals. The United States was always
aware
that these are
our minions. These are our vasals. These
are our puppets. The US always knew
this. They never considered them to be
equals. But see understand please there
is nuance in this.
Now somebody tomorrow will say on
Twitter that you have said there America
considered NATO nations to be equals.
No, the US has never considered
themselves these nations to be equal to
the US.
But the US has always treated them as if
they were equals. They the US has always
given them due respect in the past.
Okay? The US has never disrespected
these nations.
And then Trump comes along.
Trump comes along and Trump disrespects
the hell out of the NATO nations. He
makes it a point to humiliate their
leaders.
He makes it a point to disparage each
nation individually turn by turn. Right?
So that is deeply hurtful to any people.
Even if you are a vasal state, as long
as you're treated with respect, you will
swallow the fact that you are a vasal
state and you'll keep quiet about it.
But you are first of all a vasal state
and then you are repeatedly humiliated
on an ongoing basis. the people won't
tolerate that and that makes the
position of the leaders very difficult
that I see the leaders they typically
benefit in some way or the other for
being the leader of a vasal state which
means a nice puppet see these leaders
they benefit in some personal ways which
obviously you will not know about and
that's why they are okay with you know
with with steering their nation as a
vasal state but when the people get
upset and when they are being humiliated
personally
there is friction between the US and
those nations. Right?
So
that's the situation
and and beyond that beyond that the US
now is now demanding that these NATO
nations they double their contribution
to NATO's excheer now by 2030 mean
you've got to pay up double of what you
were paying until now which means
that the u social welfare measures
that these countries were spending on
now have to be cut on
these nations also have to accept
refugees from god knows what places from
certain nations. So the US and and and
these nations NATO nations can no longer
buy you know cheap Russian gas. So the
US is slowly clamping down on Europe.
They are de-industrializing Europe.
They're forcing
immigration of certain kinds into
Europe. They're forcing these nations to
pay more. They're forcing these nations,
the Americans, they're forcing the NATO
nations to spend a lot of money
supporting Ukraine. The US is putting a
tremendous amount of pressure from all
different directions on NATO nations. It
not it's not just about the respect
matter, right? That's why there is
increasing friction between the US and
NATO. And now many of these NATO nations
are kind of fed up. Do you understand?
It's it's a complex process. It's not
like you did not respect me so I will
not like you. Now, it's not like that.
It's just one of the factors. It's a
multiplicity of factors coming together.
Please understand things that it's not
just surface level analysis. We have to
do we have to look at things from a
multiplicity of angles and it all comes
together into all the pain points the
NATO nations are experiencing and that's
what is the deal. All right.
Anarva thank you very much Anurva.
Uh Tuhendra says how did academia get
hijacked by the left? How can what does
what does that mean? HWCN STD.
Okay, I don't know what HWCNS STD means.
Uh, but how did academia get hijacked by
the left?
Leftists
infiltrated academia by getting PhDs.
Okay, then becoming lecturers, then
becoming readers, then becoming
professors,
then becoming administrators, especially
administrators.
Okay, you can also hijack academia by
infiltrating
the Ministry of Education and appointing
your handpicked mediocre historians and
mediocre academics in in high positions.
So, how do you hijack an institution?
You hijack an institution by
infiltrating all the levers of the
decision-m process step by step. It's a
slow process. Sometimes it's a fast
process. So that's how academia gets
hijacked. You control the budgets. You
control the appointments. You control
the promotions. You control the
demotions. You control what kind of
people are allowed
to enter the system. You control what
kind of people are allowed to get PhDs.
You control what kind of research is
allowed, what kind of research is
prohibited. All of that you have to
start controlling. So you to control and
you have to infiltrate and take over the
decision-m process at multiple levels.
That's how you that's how you um hijack
an institution such as the academic
institution.
Panesh Pande says this um we know that
this is not a win for Pakistan. They
were just a messenger for the U
messenger board for the US. But with
Israel attacking Lebanon, is this a
pause for the US to redeem its failure?
Um
so um yeah Pakistan Pakistan is not
important. I I I rarely speak out
Pakistan. You all know this right? I
rarely speak out Pakistan because
Pakistan is not important. Pakistan is
not relevant except as a vasal state an
errand boy
a minion an asset of the United States.
That's all. It's a nuisance value for
India for Afghanistan for for Iran.
Pakistan has three neighbors. It has
India as a neighbor. It has Afghanistan
as a neighbor. It has Iran as a
neighbor. And it has Chinese occupied
Tibet also as you know a little bit. So
the three neighbors that matter, India,
Iran, Afghanistan,
each of these three neighbors dislikes
Pakistan intensely. No one likes
Pakistan
and Pakistan. It's simply a nuisance in
the region. Artificial temporary
terrorist nation. Yeah.
So that's about Pakistan. It's not that
important except as a nuisance except as
as a pain in everyone's neck neck. Um
Israel attacking Libran is this is this
a pause the US to redeem his failure.
See if there is a ceasefire then the US
gets some time to bring in re
reinforcements like I discussed like I
showed you. The US is put bringing in
more troops. The US is bringing in more
uh reinforcements, more supplies, more
arms, more ammunition, more missiles,
what not. the US is bringing in these
things into uh into the the Middle East
region. Okay. So, it's not like the US
is just sitting and waiting for two
weeks to have a discussion with Iran.
No, they're going to bring in much more.
So, this is simply a time a twoe window
of time. If if the ceasefire holds it's
a twoe window of time for the US to
regroup, to rethink and then move in for
the kill again. The war is not ending.
the US is not going to just just let
this go.
And so I'm not sure how why Iran agreed
to the ceasefire. What did Iran get out
of it? I'm I'm not really sure what they
get out of it. Uh and but the US wanted
a twoe ceasefire clearly.
But they had Pakistan play this role.
Maybe they want to blame Iran for the
failure of the ceasefire. Maybe the
Americans want to blame Iran for the
ceasefire's failure. And that's why they
had Pakistan play the role of a betrayer
and backstabber right of the spoiler and
looks like Israel doesn't want a
ceasefire and that's why they went ahead
and they knew the Israelis that one of
the points Iran had put forth one of the
conditions that Iran Iran had put forth
was that the ceasefire will extend to
Lebanon also not just to Iran but also
to to Lebanon and the Israelis the
moment this was announced they went and
bombed Lebanon so the Israelis ensured
the ceasefire doesn't happen right the
ceasefire collapses.
So that is the situation, right? The US
and Israel have both failed thus far in
their objectives. They kept kept on
changing goalposts. Day one it was about
regime change. Day three it was
something else. Day five it was
something else. Day seven it was
hormones. Day day 10 it was it was
Iran's missile program. Then it's
nuclear program. Then it's drones. This
that.
Now again when Trump said that we're
going to destroy your civilization, he
once again said regime change. Now in
yesterday's tweets again he said regime
change. So what is it that they seek?
They actually seek regime change in
Iran. Okay.
And they seek military defeat of Iran.
But that's not happened. So the US has
failed. Israel has failed. So that's why
they want to use a breather. The US
wants the breather couple of weeks to
rethink everything to restrategize to
bring in more more capacity in the
region and then attack again. They are
not serious about a ceasefire.
I expect this to once again become a
conflration maybe worse than what we've
had thus far. Right. Right. Okay.
Ashotosh, thank you very much. Ashotosh
Malgangar G, thank you.
Uh Raghav
Raghava, thank you very much. Raava G,
very nice of you. Thank you so much.
Sachidv Satya says, "In your studies of
history, have you seen any have you
noticed any common symptoms of or
patterns when an empire civilization
declines and what we can learn from
them?" Oh, absolutely. Absolutely.
It's it's a cyclical process. What
happens or what what what precipitates
the decline of an empire? Well, first of
all, the empire becomes super
successful. Okay. The empire becomes
super successful. It becomes it it
acquires more and more land, territory,
influence, power, including power over
kingdoms, kingdoms, nations that it
doesn't physically control. But it still
vasalizes them. That's why it acquires
power over them. And as a consequence,
the empire becomes super rich, very
prosperous. And the people become
accustomed to luxury etc. So why did the
empire first rise and become powerful?
Because the people were dynamic
and the people
the people were all you know geared
towards progress and rapid
transformation which means the people
were okay with being uncomfortable.
But now you have this period of
prosperity where everyone is happy
enjoying luxury.
You know there are no real problems left
anymore. So the people become soft.
They stop focusing on what matters.
They start focusing on things that don't
matter
and then
the government becomes lacks.
So essentially hard times create uh
strong men, strong men create good
times, good times create soft and weak
men and weak men create hard times. So
overall eventually you see the
civilization declining and then leaner
hungrier
peripheral forces then can then take can
can start yapping and biting at the
heels of the civilization or the empire
and eventually it collapses. It's it's a
cyclical process happens over and over
again. So what can we learn from them?
What we can learn from them is that
discomfort is important.
You can't become too too complacent, too
complacent, uh too too accustomed to
luxury and and a soft life.
Discomfort is important. It's it's it's
it's vital for a civilization remaining
strong. Okay.
Um
war keeps rejuvenating
your civilization and your empire. If
you don't have war often, well, it makes
you soft and weak. War is obviously
terrible. War is terrible for the
innocent and and the civilians. But war
is what keeps you young as a
civilization and as an empire. So, it's
it's it's a two-edged sword. On the one
hand, it keeps you young and strong and
hard. On the other hand, it is tragic.
But from a macro perspective, war is
important. You don't go to war often.
You become soft and weak and then you
get shocked by what happens in war. So
lots lots of things you can learn from
this
right. Okay. Um
brother Dana says stage two fast breed
reactor will still require initially
uranium 238. Yes I think it does. Look
uh I had put this tweet out. Uh let me
put this um for you out here. Give me a
second.
So there are three stages in India's u
three-stage
program. Okay. uh nuclear pro program,
three-stage nuclear program. Um
all right, so here we have it. Okay,
just look at this tweet. This gives you
everything you need in in in very brief
instead of going into the details. So
Prime Minister Modi on April 6th uh he
announced that India's first prototype
fastreeder reactor at Kalapakam has
attained criticality which means the
nuclear reaction has started in this
fast breeder reactor. Okay. So this is
the beginning
of the two of the second stage. So there
are some experts who will tell you that
India has reached the end of the second
stage in and we are entering the third
stage. Some experts will tell you those
experts have no idea what they're
talking about. India is now beginning
the second stage
of its three-stage nuclear program. The
first stage started in the 1960s and
we are now entering the second stage
with one reactor. All of our other
reactors are still first stage reactors.
So India is still mostly in the first
stage with one reactor that has entered
the second stage.
So if we have let's say how many
reactors do we have 25? Let's say 25.
Out of 25 one is second stage and 24 are
first stage.
Okay. So we are 4% into the second stage
and initial second stage and 96% still
first stage. That is where we are.
Understand this very clearly. Now
understand how this works. So this
three-stage program was uh this plan was
created by Dr. Homie J. Bha. Okay. So
the first stage is pressurized heavy
water reactors. This stage is complete
and operational. So we are still most of
the reactors are stage one reactors.
Okay. India runs about 22 pressurized
heavy water reactors. Heavy water is is
is is is uh proteium uh it's it's
treatitium right? No what what do you
have? You have dutium right? So heavy
water uses a heavy isotope of hydrogen.
So India runs about 22 pressurized heavy
water reactors which generate power and
accumulate plutonium 239
which is the fuel that we need to re
reach to feed second stage reactors.
Plutonium is an iso it's it's a it's an
element that's not found naturally on
our planet. Okay but we need plutonium
239 fuel to feed stage two.
Okay. So that's our stage one
pressurized heavy water reactors. We
have 22 of those roughly 22 24 whatever
the actual number is roughly 22. The
second stage is fast breeder reactors.
The second stage reactors they use the
stage 1 plutonium
as fuel and they are loaded with uranium
238 and thorium 232 around the core in a
blanket in a blanket like configuration.
Okay. So the Kalapakam fasted reactor
which is the prototype it will convert
uranium 238 into thorium 232 into more
file fuel more plutonium 239 and uranium
233 which will be bred from thorium 232.
So the pressurized so so the fast
breeder reactors in stage two they will
breed more fuel than they burn.
Imagine a reactor that burns fuel but
produces more fuel. So that's a stage
two reactor. Okay, fast breeder reactor.
So the Kalapakam FBR frostbreeder
reactor is now sustaining a controlled
fish chain reaction. Okay, it's
successfully uh sustaining a controlled
fish and chain reaction. So a kalapakum
type type reactor, a fast bidder reactor
will produce maybe a few grams, maybe a
few kilograms,
okay, of uranium 233
per year.
per year. So we're going to need a lot
of these reactors if we have to reach
stage three whenever it happens. So
stage three is advanced heavy water
reactors on thorium. So first of all in
stage two you need um uranium 238. Okay.
And you also need thorium 232.
So you need uranium 238 and thorium 232
both.
Um and without the thodium you will not
be able to breed the uranium 233 in
stage two. So in stage two you need
thorium. Okay. Stage three is advanced
heavy water reactors. This is the end
goal. Advanced heavy water reactors will
use the uranium 233 bred in stage 2 as
their main fuel along with thorium 232.
And India has the world's largest
reserves of thorium. So this will give
India virtually inexhaustible indigenous
clean nuclear energy for centuries. So
India is now beginning its transition
into stage two and we have demonstrated
indigenous mastery of one of the most
complex reactor technologies without
foreign assistance. It's uh it's a great
achievement. No question about that.
It's a great great achievement. But we
have a long way to go. It's going to get
it's going to take decades for us to
reach stage three because a fast breeder
reactor like Kalapakam so Kalapakam is a
prototype. It's an experimental reactor.
We're going to operate it for a while
for two three years. We're going to
initiate the breeding reaction by by
having thorium in the blanket around the
the core. Okay? And we're going to see
how it works. At what rate do uh is it
generating is it breeding the uranium
233 fuel and the plutonium. We're going
to have to see that based on our study
of how this re this reactor performs for
a while for two three years.
maybe four, five years. Then we will
build one more reactor. Then we'll see
how that performs. Then we'll build two,
three more. Eventually we'll build a few
dozens of reactors.
And then let's say each reactor produces
a couple of kilograms or whatever. Maybe
5 kg, 10 kg of uranium 23 233 per year.
We're going to need tons of that. So
we're going to have to run these
reactors for decades each of them.
Hopefully, we have 50 of those. Let's
say, let's say we're going to have to
run them for 10, 20 years to get enough
fuel for stage three. So, minimum 10,
20, 30 years to reach stage three
sitting sitting where we are right now.
Maybe 40, 50 years depending on how
quickly we we we
uh kick off stage two, how quickly we
scale up in stage two. So, we are just
starting now. Understand? We just
starting stage two finally. Finally. But
we have a long long way to go before we
can start stage three with the first
stage three reactor which will also be a
prototype and that will take 10 20 30
years to get going and then so maybe 50
60 years from now we will have proper
stage three going hopefully in 50 60
years.
Okay. It is a long long process my dear
friends. All right.
Okay.
The Eternal Witness is a new member.
Thank you very much, The Eternal
Witness, and welcome to this channel's
membership. I really appreciate it.
W says, "Please upload new Askab
episodes on Spotify." Yes, I shall have
it done at the earliest. Thank you for
the reminder. Appreciate that.
Uh, Soldier Boy says, "Your take on UNOI
sir? Where's our nation heading?" UNOI,
one nation, one election. I haven't
thought about this. I look into
geopolitics, history, science and one
nation, one election
on paper, it sounds like a good idea.
I've not put given much thought to this.
But in India's electoral democracy,
which is a Westminster style democracy,
let's say you have one year,
one nation, one election. So let's say
in a certain year you have all the state
elections and the general election at
the same time in one year. Okay.
So each state is going to vote
differently. The nation is going to vote
differently for the parliament of India.
And let's say in some some states you
have coalition governments or you have a
hung assembly. Then what do you do?
If if there's a co coalition government
in some states let's say uh we have 20
odd states. Let's say five states you
have hung assemblies or you have
coalition governments and after 2 years
3 years these governments fall
and the assembly is hung and you need
new elections then what do you do then
after 2 years only do you once again
have one nation one election or do you
put that state in the president's rule
until the next cycle of elections 5
years down the line from the initial
starting point what do you do for one
nation one election we need to
transition to a presidential form of
moment.
This parliamentary system, this
Westminster democracy system will not
work. If you want to have one nation,
one election in a presidential style
system, once a president is elected for
the nation, that person takes on the
role of the executive leadership and
that person stays for four years, 5
years, whatever it is. And if you apply
the presidential style system to states
then you will have state assemblies but
the state will have a chief minister or
a governor who will rule for 5 years or
four years whatever let's say 5 years
for India. So even if the state assembly
is a hung hung assembly or whatever the
person who was elected as governor or
chief minister will stay for 5 years
they can't that person can't be removed
unless there's impeachment which is very
rare. So if you want a one nation
election, it will not work with this
current system which is ridiculous and
which which the system is not suitable
for India.
For 80 years roughly almost we have been
saddled with a system that is terrible
for the country.
Ideally we should have a presidential
file system. Then you then you can make
one nation one election work. Otherwise
you can't. It just won't work. It's it
will not be practical. It will not be
feasible in in the real world. On paper
it'll look nice. In the real world it'll
break.
Sergeant Skylin says Rafal versus 57.
Look, if the French are unwilling to
give us the codes, the source code of
the Rafal, then it makes no sense to pay
so much money for those fighter plates.
So I would say if the French after
paying so much money, if they are not
willing to give us the source codes,
then we should not go for the Rafael.
Dump it. go for the soa 57 and acquire
the full technology including source
codes the Russians will give it and for
a less lesser price but the main thing
is India should now focus because these
aircraft will take years to come even if
we start the production now it'll take 5
7 10 years for the first aircrafts to
start rolling out because you to first
build the factories the production lines
assembly lines all those things takes
time so it'll take at least 10 years for
these things to become for the first
aircraft to start ruling out of the of
the assembly lines. Until then, what do
we do? We have to start focusing full
scale on ballistic missiles, cruise
missiles and drones.
You have that it can completely offset
the the the shortfall in in fighter
planes and the future is going to be all
AI and robotics. The human operated
fighter planes are going to be like
dinosaurs very soon. So India needs to
wake up and realize this is the 21st
century no longer the 20th century where
the heads of a lot of these planners
seem to be right a lot of our planners
etc they seem to have their heads still
in the 20th century they're still
thinking from the 20th century
perspective it has to be drones and
missiles now so I would say
focus on the AMCA let it however long it
takes focus on the indigenous jet engine
however long it takes in the meanwhile
If the French are being difficult then
dump the rafal and get the soy no matter
how good or bad it is at least we'll be
able to manufacture it entirely over
here in India and then we'll be able to
if required tweak it and improve it
which you'll be great at doing actually
yeah so I would I am leading towards a
soy even if it's not the best aircraft
in the world so what at least it will be
your aircraft because you'll be able to
control every aspect of it that's better
than having some fantastic aircraft that
you can't control and you need
permission to update every time. You
don't want that, right? Okay.
Hot potato says, "What path could lead
India to a presidential democracy or
dictatorship? What could trigger it? Is
changing this changing the system still
possible? Thank you. I have no idea. I
am no expert in India's constitution and
laws and whatnot. Um the constitution is
impossible to understand and read.
Hundreds of pages, right? If you ask any
two constitutional experts, they will
disagree on various things.
Um
and I don't think the pres the Indian
constitution allows you to transition to
a different system. The constitution of
India is such that it doesn't allow you
to transition to a different system. The
constitution of India doesn't allow you
to scrap the constitution.
I'm sure there is there must be some way
ways or means of changing the system but
the process will be incredibly difficult
because you're going to need twothirds
majorities in all the state assemblies
and god knows what else. I'm not sure
how it works. It's incredibly difficult.
Yeah. So how does India transition?
Forget about dictatorship. Okay.
Dictatorship is completely out of the
question from the constitutional
perspective. But let's say the con we
want to transition from the westminster
style prime ministerial system to a
presidential system. How do you do it
within the ambit of the constitution of
India? You have to ask a constitutional
expert about this. I think the the way
forward will be very difficult. So how
do you make it happen?
Uh you will need a situation where there
is some
look it's all I'm giving you an academic
hypothetical situation. I'm not
recommending any of this first of all.
Okay, this is completely academic and
completely hypothetical. Maybe let's say
hypothetically someday, complete
hypothetical scenario, maybe there's a
war and whoever is ruling the country,
prime minister has to impose a uh not
emergency on the country.
Okay. And then when there's an
emergency, you can do stuff like what
the great Madame Indra Gandhi G had
done. She changed our constitution,
changed the preamble, what not. She had
this done. So maybe whoever is the prime
minister at that time because there's an
emergency and the he or she has
emergency powers, maybe they can change
the constitution at the time and give
the the the the president of what Mrs.
Gandhi had done. Maybe that's one way to
uh quickly have a change in the system.
Yeah, maybe that's one scenario. I'm not
sure if it will be completely
constitutional or not or whatever. But
I'm sure that what was done in 1975 or
thereabouts was also not completely
constitutional but it became part of the
constitution. So maybe that's one
scenario that could hypothetically work
in a in a completely hypothetical
scenario
perhaps. I'm sure changing the system is
possible. Changing the system is always
possible
but it is very hard to do in normal
circumstances.
You will need extraordinary
circumstances for these things to
happen. In normal regular circumstances
where everything is business as usual,
it's almost impossible to change the
system. But if the country is is it
finds itself under extraordinary
circumstances, then things are possible.
Hey okay. Okay. So this is the same
question once again but yes that's the
answer that I can offer you. Uh Agni
Rudra says good evening. Well good
evening to you. Uh watching your channel
for more than two years. Thank you so
much. Thank you so much. Agnudra, uh,
thank you for all the knowledge you have
shared over the years. It changed the
way I think about GP. You are very
welcome. Uh, GP, what is GP?
Geopolitics. Okay. Geopolitics. You're
very welcome. I'm very glad that I could
I could help you in some way. Thank you
so much. Thank you so much.
The Eternal Witness has gifted one Aijit
Cha membership, one channel membership
to someone, some one lucky person. So I
thank you on behalf of the one lucky
person and I thank you on my behalf as
well. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Arismantic says is Trump trying to
exhaust in Iran's missile stock and
drones by getting NATO involved too.
Iran would extend its target range to
Europe if NATO joins question mark.
Uh
see the situation right now is that
the Americans and Israelis have
have have
uh done tremendous damage to Iran.
They've bombed universities. They
they've bombed bombed children's
schools. They've bombed factories.
They've bombed uh uh refineries. They've
bombed um
petroleum reserves, oil reserves. They
have bombed uh military military
installations whatever they can. They've
bombed bomb bomb. They've bombed cities.
They bombed Thran. They've done
assassinations.
So Iran is in a situation where I it
most likely is not currently
manufacturing or producing more missiles
and drones. Whatever stockpile it had
accumulated, that's all it has to play
with.
That's most likely the situ scenario
because to manufacture more missiles and
drones you need factories and factories
you can't bring underground most likely
unless Iran has done the almost
impossible
and factories the Americans would have
identified where are the factories and
they would have bombed them and if a
factory is bombed you can't manufacture
new missiles and drones there because
it's all destroyed so most likely
Iran is not able to produce more
missiles and drones right
and whatever stockpile they have, that's
all they have to play with. That's what
I imagine is the most likely scenario.
So if Trump brings in more arms, more
ammunition, more missiles, more whatever
and forces Iran to keep firing missiles
and drones, then in that case, if the US
has more missiles and drones than Iran
or more targets to hit at than Iran has
drones and missiles, then they could
potentially exhaust Iran's missile stock
and roads possibly. Um
so but Iran would have most likely
they would have planned for these
scenarios
and if Iran is is in a situation where
it's it's starting to slowly run out of
their stocks then they'll be more
careful with their missiles and drones
and how they're using them. So it's a
game of cat and mouse on both sides. So
I personally have no idea how many
missiles and how many drones Iran has.
They probably would have more than
100,000 drones when the war began and
they probably would have had at least
10,000 missiles when the war began. So
what are the stocks now? I'm not sure
how many have they fired. Maybe a few
thousand they fired missiles which means
they perhaps have a few thousand
missiles left and maybe they have a few
10,000 drones left perhaps.
So um it depends on various factors on
how many actual missiles and drones the
Iranians have. Most likely they have way
more missiles and drones than the
Americans can can have globally. Most
likely. Um, now what if so, so what
Trump can do is get NATO involved, drag
NATO into the into the war. But how does
NATO get involved? He wants them to NATO
to to send ships to to the Hormos
region. Well, if they send if NATO sends
ships to the Hormuz region and they try
to fight Iran, Iran will take out those
ships.
Ships are essentially floating targets.
You can defend them for a while, but if
you send just too many drones, the ship
is a s set sitting duck.
But Trump wants this to happen. He wants
NATO to make make the move and send
warships and other whatever assets to
the region. I think eventually he'll be
able to force NATO to do that. But if
NATO gets involved, will Iran start
targeting NATO nations?
Uh I think it's the likelihood is less.
Right. I I imagine that Iran will not
want to start fighting everybody in the
world. Um
if NATO gets involved, I think Iran will
strike at the NATO assets in the Gulf
region, not the NATO nations over there.
Unless I am completely
um wrong about how Iran thinks.
Satellite says, "Welcome back. Long time
no see." Well, I have been here every
week. Maybe you're not get getting
notifications from YouTube. Perhaps
that's a possibility that maybe you're
not get getting notifications, but uh
it's good to see you once again. So,
welcome back to you as well. I've been
doing the live streams to two three live
streams per week since the war began,
but it's good to see you again. So,
thank you so much and good to see you
back. All right.
Min says, "Can the US bring thousands of
missiles in just two weeks?" Very hard
to do that. It depends on what kind of
missiles we're discussing. See, if
you're talking about ballistic missiles,
ballistic missiles are very large and
they're very hard to transport. Very
hard to transport because they're so
large. Ballistic missiles aren't small.
If you're talking about surfaceto-air
missiles like the man pads or Stinger
missiles, the US can bring in lots in
two weeks. If you're talking about a
cruise missiles like the Tomahawks,
I'm not sure how many tomahawks the US
has globally. Uh let's try and find out.
Let's ask our friend Google.
Um, let's see. How many Tomahawk
missiles
how many Tomahawk missiles does the
United States have in total and how many
does it produce every year?
Let us see what Google's AI has to say.
So, as of early 26, the US is estimated
to have a total inventory of about 3,000
3,000 Tomahawk missiles
um following heavy usage in recent
conflicts. Production is currently low
with about 100 missiles expected this
year and there are plans to increase
production in 2027 to 785 less than a
thousand. So currently the US has
between 3,000 to 4,000 active missiles
and over 850 of these were used in the
first month of the American war against
Iran.
So if it's Tomahawk missiles, these
cruise missiles, well the US only has
3,000 4,000 and about a thousand of
these have been used up in this Iran
war. Roughly roughly a thousand
approximately order of magnitude
thousand
and there are other enemies the US has
to worry about.
So I think it's very difficult for the
US to bring in thousands of missiles in
two weeks. Even if they have the
capability to transport missiles, do
they have that many missiles?
That's the big question. Very hard for
the US to do that.
Okay.
Um Shivan says, "You were right about
the Indian prestige complex. Everyone's
calling this a failure of our policy
since we are the land of Gandhi and
should have mediated instead of
Pakistan. My entire ex timeline is just
about this."
See, understand. Okay. It's an
interesting topic. Let's let's let's
unpack this a little bit more. So
Pakistan has mediated and they've
mediated disastrously.
They have essentially taken a knife and
stabbed Iran in the back.
Okay. They've betrayed and backstabbed
Iran. That's what Pakistan has done. But
they have mediated. They have been the
mediator between the US is between on
one side the US and Israel other side
Iran. Okay. So lots of Indians are
saying why was India not involved in
this process? Why did India not mediate?
India is a bigger nation than Pakistan,
more relevant nation, more prestigious.
We we should have done this and our
standing has has decreased. It's fallen
in the world and Pakistan standing has
has increased in the world. That's what
some Indians are saying. Many Indians
are possibly saying this. Understand
this. The first question is should India
have mediated? Hm.
See, it's like this. Pay attention.
Let's say there are two guys fighting or
two nations fighting or three nations
fighting. So there are two on one side
and there's another one here and they
are fighting each other. Now
if you want to mediate
then you will be able to mediate only if
both sides agree that you should be a
mediator.
If one side says I don't like you, I
don't want you to mediate and one side
says I want you. But if the other side
says I don't trust you, I don't like
you, I don't want you, then you can't be
a mediator.
So for you to be able to mediate,
both sides in the conflict must trust
you and want you to mediate. Only then
can you mediate. Now tell me, does the
US want India as a mediator? No,
the US doesn't want India as a mediator.
The US wants their trusted servant
Pakistan as a mediator
so that they can do all kinds of
shenanigans or they can have Pakistan do
nasty things.
And Israel also trusts Pakistan. By the
way, the US and Israel are on the same
side. They are essentially at least in
the context of this war, they are
essentially the same thing, same entity,
US Israel. And they trust Pakistan.
Pakistan is a US asset. It's also an
Israeli asset by the way.
News to you. Okay, good for you.
So
if the US doesn't want India to ne to
mediate, then how can India mediate
and if the US doesn't want India to
mediate, is that some disaster for
India? I say great for India. We did not
start this war.
We are this is not our war. We are not
involved in the war.
And if one of the sides in the war
doesn't want us to mediate, well, we'll
stay out of it. What do we anyway get by
mediating?
Do we get something? Do we do do we gain
something from mediate? By mediating, we
gain nothing.
So to hell with prestige, look out for
your national interest.
And Pakistan's prestige has fallen now
very badly. Look at Twitter. Look at
what the Iranians are saying. Look at
what half the world is saying about
Pakistan. Pakistan is an unreliable
intermediary. Pakistan is a treacherous
intermediary. Pakistan has backstabbed
both sides or one side.
JD van said that you know what it's a
genuine misunderstanding. Our mediator
did not convey the right information to
both sides. Pakistan is being made to be
the fall guy. Pakistan is okay with it.
Pakistan is completely fine with with
the Americans saying whatever they want
from Pakistan as long as Pakistan gets
what it wants which is that generals get
some money.
That's all.
Okay. So this is not a failure of our
policy. Our policy our our government's
policy is to look out for India to to
look out for India's national interests
and mediating in this matter is not in
any way advancing our national interest.
Okay. So whoever is calling this out,
they must be newly minted geopolitical
experts, but they have no idea what
they're talking about. Right. Okay.
Aki Janu says, "If the US leaves GCC,
Iran becomes a local power." Right.
Right. Iran has already become a
regional power, a great regional power.
You you could say that Iran has emerged
as a consequence of this war as a global
great power. Not a superpower but the
most powerful nation in West Asia.
Okay.
If Iran decides it can destroy any of
the nations in West Asia, it has that
that kind of power. Maybe Iran also did
not realize how powerful it is, but now
it does.
So whether the US leaves the GCC or not,
whether the US leaves the region
geographically or not, Iran is now the
most powerful nation in West Asia.
And that is something the entire world
can see now.
It's not a local power. It's a great
power in the region.
It has more missile and drone firepower
than India.
It can wipe Pakistan out tomorrow
morning if they want.
Iran can do that to Pakistan. Iran can
flatten Pakistan tomorrow morning if it
wants.
Okay.
Right.
Arian Gorty says, um, how has the
influence that our orange fool in the US
has over Pakistan impacted the outcomes
of past wars from a BAT perspective? As
an Indian-American, I don't understand
why Pakistan is our ally.
Okay.
Um, how has the influence that your
orange fool means Trump? So, how has the
influ influence that Trump has over
Pakistan
impacted the outcomes of p past wars
from a bat perspective? See, when we
talk about past wars, the one past war
that comes to mind is the 2025 operation
Synindor, which was a three-day
conflict. It was an aerial conflict.
There was no naval dimension. There was
no land dimension. It was an aan aerial
conflict. So it was a three-day war
between India and Pakistan be before
that the last war was 1999
was it Cargill war right was it 98 99
whatever year it was it was 99 most
likely or 2000 whichever year it was
cargill war 2001
okay since I'm not able to remember let
me just quickly see
cargill war which year
okay 1999 like I said first all
So before operation Shindur, you had the
Cargill war in 1999
and in 1999 Trump was nowhere near being
anything like the US president. He was
just a real estate guy at the time. Uh
so the orange fool came to power like
you say orange fool. He came to power in
2016 as you will know very well. He went
out of power in 2020 and then he's back
in power 2024 onwards. In that period of
time, there's only been one war which is
the operation sindur three-day war and
Trump had a big role to play in ending
the war because India's suddenly visible
domination of Pak over Pakistan and the
damage India started doing over the in
the last day of the war on on uh against
Pakistan the US suddenly became alarmed
and they rushed in and they essentially
you could say forced India to stop the
war.
The Indian government doesn't agree with
this. The Indian government says that
the Pakistanis begged us to stop. That's
why we we stopped the war and it's a
paused war. It's not an ended war.
Whatever. Right. Um
so Trump had had a role to play in
ending the operation war. uh beyond that
any any other past wars Trump had no
relevance or or or or
uh influence
or role to play in any past wars. Um as
an Indian-American you don't understand
why Pakistan is your is America's ally.
Pak see the US seeks to project power
everywhere in the world. The US seeks to
establish specific balances of power in
various theaters or regions. So in West
Asia, the US wants a certain balance of
power. It wants all the nations arranged
in in specific ways with certain amounts
of power. You could assign a certain
hard power score to each nation and you
have a US ally which is Israel. You have
other US assets like Saudi Arabia and
other countries and you have an American
adversary such as Iran. So you want the
whole region to be balanced in such a
way that the American allies and and
puppets have cumulatively more power
than the American adversary which is
Iran. So that's how they have created a
balance of power in in West Asia after
2003 by wiping out Iraq. In the Indian
subcontinent, the Americans want India
to be encircled. They have a containment
policy against India. And one of the
greatest tools to leverage in the
subcontinent is Pakistan, right? And
that's why the Americans always prop up
Pakistan
and that's been the case since the 20th
century. Right? After the USSR invaded
Afghanistan, Pakistan became very
important for the US. And Pakistan was
very happy to play a constructive role
in in doing whatever the Americans
wanted them to do as long as they got
their green backs.
So Pakistan is a mercenary state. US has
always preferred to work with
dictatorships. They don't like to work
with democracies. Democracies are hard
to control. Dictatorships are very easy
to control. The US loves working with
dictators. And that's why the Americans
have always propped up Pakistan
and Pakistan plays a great role as as as
a nuisance for India as a tool to bleed
India with. See, as if you are the US,
you don't want to get your hands dirty
and do nasty stuff. So, you have
somebody else do it for you.
So we know that from 1980 roughly
onwards the Pak the Americans have been
funding and financing Pakistani
activities
and that's the time when Pakistan not
only was involved in Afghanistan but
also in terrorism in India against India
in Punjab and then in Jammu and Kashmir
who funded and financed Pakistani
terrorism against India. It was the
United States. It is what it is. Right.
Right. Okay.
Okay. Wun Bajage says,
"Does the education one receives shape a
person's moral values, right versus
wrong and good versus bad for society,
or is it independent?"
See, whatever
um experiences you have during your
formative years are going to shape your
worldview for the rest of your life.
What are your formative years? the years
when you were a child and a teenager.
And when you were a child and when
you're a teenager, you spend more time
in your classroom with your teachers
than you spend with your parents.
Especially in today's world when your
parents are all busy working, toiling
away.
So you are more influenced
by your teachers and your education
system than by your own parents.
And who shapes the values?
Who who determines the values that the
teachers and education system and
textbooks impart to you? It's the
government mostly and whoever is running
the private educational institutions.
And whatever you learn from your
teachers and textbooks in school and
college and university, you're going to
absorb that because you genuinely
believe as a child that your your elders
are telling you the truth.
So the education you receive it does
shape
most often permanently your values, your
moral values, how you see right versus
wrong, whether you can think or not. If
you do think then in what ways do you
think? What are your thought patterns?
What are the mental models you use? If
you use any, what is your conception of
good and what is your conception of bad?
What is right, what is wrong? How do you
do decision? How do you make decisions?
All those things, all of that is shaped
by the education you receive. It's
shaped by the important uh people you
see as role models in your in your early
life. Typically, you will see some
teachers as role models and people who
are very influential in your life.
So, it's it's
it's most important
you know the the role that education uh
plays in your early life. It's going to
shape the rest of your life unless you
are strong enough to completely
deprogram yourself. So it's very
important the education system, the
education you receive is extremely
extremely influential. It's it's
critical. It's vital in in shaping uh
your entire worldview as an adult.
Hotspotto says if history is written by
the victors in the internet a in an
internet age, how will history of the
future be? History of the future. Okay,
let's say 100 years from now, what kind
of history will be written about today?
Well, if the internet still exists 100
years from from now, then whoever
controls the internet will be will
determine how the history is written.
See, today you will see if you try to
search on on Google um what's happened
in the past 3 days of the Iran versus US
Israel war. It will say that so and so
things have happened and these are
confirmed and so and so things have
happened and they're not confirmed, not
verified. So when you say what is
verified what is not verified it means
it will say that whatever the US
government and the west has said has
happened is verified information and
whatever Iran is claiming is un
unverified information. You can see
already there's a bias here. The Iranian
government is making certain statements
but those are unverified according to
Google and BBC and CNN and whatever
claims the US is making and Israel is
making and the west is making those are
verified statements.
Right? So history is already being
written by those forces that control the
internet that own the internet.
Even if the US loses this war, the
internet will show the will will will
show it in a certain way.
Right? So assuming the internet remains
the way it is right now for 100 years or
it is controlled by the same forces then
the history that you will see 100 years
down the line will be the history that
that the west wants to portray. That's
how it's going to be written.
Rut Rujakulkarnney thank you very much
uh for becoming a new member and welcome
to the channel's membership. Thank you
very much.
Groove Street Hobie says, "Does
pressurized past breeder reactor use a
uranium 238 blanket with plutonium fuel,
meaning no thorium blanket yet, and thus
no plutonium 2 33 stabilization, which
is deferred to stage three.
In stage two, if you want to breed
uranium 233,
you're going to need
thorium in the blanket along with the
plutonium fuel.
So the core is going to be plutonium and
the blanket you're going to have
thorium.
It's going to breed uranium 233.
Okay? and the uranium 233 which we're
going to breed in in stage two. It's
going to be used along with thorium
in stage three.
That's how it goes. So a fast breeder
reactor it breeds new fuel. It breeds
more fuel which you want to use in stage
three. The fuel that is being bred is
uranium 233. For that to happen, for
that reaction to happen which breeds
uranium 233, you need a thorium blanket.
You can run a pressurized fast bidder
reactor without the thorium blanket but
in that case it will only generate heat
which gives you electricity. It will not
breed the ur uranium 233. So if you want
to use it as a breeder not just an
electricity generator then you need a
thorium blanket.
Okay. So without a thorium blanket, the
reactor still operates but it doesn't
breed new fuel uranium 233. It only
generates electricity heat which is then
converted into electricity. But we want
to breed uranium 233 for the third
stage. For that you need a thorium
blanket. So initially what you do you
have the reactor go critical when it's a
new reactor and you stabilize the
reactor. You stabilize the reactions.
You control them with the cadmium etc
rods and all that. You do that. You have
it run for a while, few weeks, maybe a
couple of months. And then you introduce
the thorium blanket and see
at what rate is it breeding uranium 233.
So you can operate it without the
thorium blanket but then it defeats the
whole purpose of breeding uranium 233.
Okay, that's the deal.
Right. Jooshi says apparently Pakistan
getting claps.
How do we care?
How will the US and Iran expose their
lies? Why will the US expose Pakistani
lies when the Americans are the
sponsors?
Okay, let me read the whole thing.
Apparently Pakistan is getting claps.
How will the US or Iran expose their
lies on a global stage such that they
are blamed for the violation? Clever
move by Pakistan. First of all, Pakistan
is not important. I don't know why
Indians are so obsess obsessed with
Pakistan. Secondly, Pakistan has
betrayed and backstabbed Iran.
They will not dare betray and backstab
the US.
If they have done such a thing, the
Americans will punish them tremendously.
And the Americans seem to be very
pleased with Pakistan.
Okay? The Americans aren't saying a
thing against Pakistan. The Iranians are
very upset with Pakistan. So, it tells
you who has been on the receiving end of
the backstab by Pakistan.
The Pakistani prime minister yesterday
claimed that we have successfully
engineered a ceasefire. Well, is the
ceasefire holding?
Now both sides are blaming each other
and one side is also blaming Pakistan.
The Pakistani prime minister very
clearly wrote yesterday. Okay, let me
show you once again.
He very clearly wrote yesterday that the
ceasefire includes Lebanon. See you look
here.
See,
he tweeted this yesterday.
The ceasefire will be effective uh
immediately
and it will be it will include li
Lebanon and elsewhere. So Sharif said
Lebanon and elsewhere and the Israelis
immediately violated that. Right. So do
you think this is a successful move
operation whatever by Pakistan? It's
been a colossal failure.
Right. And not just has has the
ceasefire
process, engineering process failed, it
has betrayed is Iran.
So what the Pakistanis did, okay, is
they
the the Iranians have a 10-point
proposal and the Americans have a
15-point proposal and these two have to
somehow be viable starting points for a
negotiation. So the Pakistanis took
these to 10 points from Iran and they
gave it to the Americans.
Trump said that we are fine with that.
It's a workable starting point and so on
and then the Israelis go ahead and start
bombing Lebanon which was not supposed
to happen as per the cispire cisfire
thing. Then then JD Vance goes and says
that you know uh this was a genuine
misunderstanding. The mediator has seems
to have given the wrong sets of things
to to both sides or whatever. So he's
indirectly blaming Pakistan for this
right that Pakistan somehow has messed
up. But overall what's happened is that
the Pakistanis gave the ill the illusion
to the Iranians that the ceasefire would
work that you can rely on the Americans
and Israelis and uh the exact opposite
happened and even Iran was bombed
yesterday. There were explosions in
Thran. Allegedly the UAE bombed some
some petroleum refineries or whatever
prochemical complex of Iran. So Iran has
been backstabbed and betrayed
and even if you disregard what's
happened to Iran and that the fact that
they have again closed the state of
Hormuz. No, you don't disregard that.
You if you disregard the Leberan bombing
and all that the ceasefire has failed
and Pakistan has been exposed as a
duplicitous nation. So by for what
reason are they getting claps? From whom
are they getting claps? They're getting
a tremendous amount of abuse from the
Iranians. I'll not put it on Twitter
because on the screen because the
language is very abusive in Persian and
some Persian abusive words are also
understandable intelligible in in India.
So we don't want to see that here on
this screen on this channel here. Um so
I don't know who's clapping for
Pakistan. There must be the same old
usual suspect in India who always bat
for Pakistan who may be clapping for it.
I don't give a damn about them. Those
people are irrelevant dinosaurs. Okay.
But Pakistan has been totally exposed
exposed and there is nothing clever
about this move. The only clever thing
is that they will get a pat on the back
in private from the Americans. Okay,
good job. You did a good job. That's it.
Okay.
Shivaj Rajput says, "Watching you since
your Arian invasion video 6 years ago on
the SAM talks channel." Well, that was a
long time ago. Thank you so much for
having been such a longtime uh watcher
of mine. Thank you. Uh I do remember
that forum. Yes. Uh how likely is
operation Synindhu 2.0 in 2026?
Well, the likelihood is non zero. The
probability is non-zero which means it
could happen. But see, understand this.
Right now, India faces one problem which
is the fact that
the Navic system, the IRSS system is no
longer fully functional.
It's no longer giving us accurate
positioning information. What is the
Navic or IRNSS system? It's a satellite
positioning system.
In a satellite positioning system, you
have satellites, a bunch of satellites
that are placed into geostationary orbit
above the Earth.
So geostationary orbit means the
satellite is about roughly 36,000
kilometers above the Earth's surface.
And then you have you need at least four
satellites to give you signal so that
you can get a proper fix of your
location coordinates latitude and
longitude in in you know accurately on
the earth. If less than four satellites
are operational your latitude longitude
coordinates will drift by kilometers
maybe hundreds of kilometers at least
100 kilometers which means you don't get
accurate data accurate positioning
information. Now, if you're launching
cruise missiles and you want the cruise
missile to hit exactly where you want it
to hit, you need accurate positioning
data from your satellites and now NAVIC
is not working properly. It's not giving
you accurate data. So, you can rely on
GPS which is American and when there's a
war the Americans will switch off GPS
for your military. Then what will you
do? You can will you ask the Chinese for
BEu? They won't give it. Maybe Russia
may help you with GLONAS.
But why have we allowed Navi to fail? It
did not fail suddenly. We could see the
failure coming a decade ago.
We you can say you know things went
wrong which we didn't expect. The the
PSLV rockets failed multiple times. Well
that also you could have foreseen in the
1980s. The Aryan rockets failed in the
same way. There was a spy involved in
this. There was sabotage. There could be
sabotage in the PSMV system also. So
can't you foresee all these things that
these things could go wrong? So this is
a problem and because of that I think it
doesn't make sense for India right now
to go to war with Pakistan until we have
a fully functional NA system again which
means we'll have to launch at least two
three satellites more at least a couple
of satellites more
and I think the satellite launches are
planned for sometime later this year
perhaps
so that is India you know not
you know being caught napping a little
bit
so I It doesn't makes make a lot of
sense for us to have operation sindur
until we have a fully functional Navic
system. And there will be some very very
intelligent G you know experts who will
tell you that India has low earth or
satellites LEO satellites low earth
orbit satellites which will do the job
of Navik which is nonsense. Low earth
orbit satellites are spy satellites that
take pictures detailed high resolution
pictures of the earth's surface. And
these satellites, LEO satellites, they
typically operate between 150 to 500 or
700 km above the earth's surface. So
they can't give you positioning
information like the geostationary
satellites do which are at an altitude
of 36,000 km.
The low earth orbit satellites are at
200 to 500 maybe 700 km above the earth
surface. They can't do the job of a
navic satellite of a GPS satellite. So
those experts who will tell you that
because we have LEO we are fine. They
have no idea what they're talking about.
Okay. So um that's the deal. So I think
India should stay away from any military
entanglements this year if possible
until we have Navic operational again.
Mr. Rohit says loved your America
series. Any upcoming series Britain?
Well, I'll have to resume the
understanding America series first and
complete it and only then can I go
towards Britain. Uh so right now um
it's on pause right now because of
whatever is happening in the world right
now. But eventually I will resume that
because I need to I've just you know
that understanding America series has a
long way to go before I can move on to
something else.
Goat ghost says latest deed by Shri
Cookies
ignored by the legacy media. Are you
talk Shri Cookies?
What is Shri Cookies? Are you talking
about the cookie terrorists in Manipur?
They have done something very nasty in
Manipur, right? And obviously the legacy
media will ignore that.
And I'm not sure why this is being
allowed to happen.
That's the internet blackout in Manipur
now. So if you are an entrepreneur, if
you are a business person who relies on
the internet, your business is over.
Finished.
This is the way we treat our far eastern
states. And then we wonder why that
these people why these people they they
they are upset with us. Why they feel
like we are giving them step treatment.
Then we wonder why there is separatism
and all that. I'm not saying I'm
defending separatism. Absolutely not.
Separatism can never be tolerated. But
do you understand? You're creating the
situation, the scenario, the the the
fertile soil for the for such
discontented people to take up stupid
actions.
Right.
We should treat the people of every
state of India the same. Right. Give
everybody the same opportunities.
Make sure that nobody faces terrorism.
That nobody has to face weeks without
internet.
We should do that right and that we are
not able to provide to the people of
Manipur. The indigenous people of
Manipur the foreigners who are on
Manipur territory they getting
everything they want. So big problem in
Manipur. Manipur is an ongoing disaster.
Ongoing disaster.
Right angle says why is the government
allowing foreign AI everywhere? Is BJP
deep state is compromised? Nitin Gudkar
is bringing Tesla in India now allowed
foreign AI in agree and road
I will not comment about the political
angle whether BJP is compromised or not
whether Mr. Gudkari brings in I have no
idea what's happening. Okay. I don't
look at that. I look at the geopolitical
angle outside of India. So no comments
about the the the local politics
domestic politics but I am very strongly
a very strong proponent of India not
allowing foreign technology to
infiltrate various parts of India
especially artificial intelligence
especially a satellite internet like
Starlink. India should not allow any of
these things. India should develop
sovereign AI. We should not allow
foreign AI to infiltrate our system, our
government, our bureaucracy, which seems
to be happening, which is unfortunate if
it happens.
Okay. Empty boxes, insidious
preparation. How to become a competent
lieutenant? I am not a military person.
I cannot tell you.
No idea.
Um, so I'm sorry. I'm not the right
person to answer this question.
Competent lieutenant. What is the role
of a lieutenant? Where does the that
rank stand in the hierarchy of military
ranks? I I'm not very clear about this.
Sorry. Very sorry. That's a very
specific military question which is why
if I attempt to answer it, I may
actually end up misleading you because
I'm not sure. So, I better not answer
you at all because I don't know. Okay.
Sorry.
Um Ara Prabhare says, "Big fan." Thank
you very much, sir. Given today's global
climate, is an EU passport still
advantageous? What is its key benefits
and drawbacks?
Well, the key benefit of an EU passport
is that there's a big there's this big
shenhen zone that you can travel in and
live in and work in without any
restrictions.
So, it gives you visa-free access to a
very large portion of Western Europe,
most nations in Western Europe. That's a
great advantage. So, if you have a
decent amount of money, you can go and
settle down wherever you want. You can
move out and go to another country if
you want. no restrictions, no problems,
right? So that's that's a great
advantage to have. And all most of the
EU nations, they have very high living
standards.
There are issues in every nation more
these days than before, but overall
they've got way better living standards
than India, right? Um so overall, if you
if you ask about right now today,
it's still great to have an EU uh
passport, right? You can go and settle
in whichever country you want. You can
move to whatever country as and when you
feel like or as and when you desire or
need to. Right? So it gives you great
mobility. If you have a EU visa, you can
visit lots of countries outside of the
EU without visas. If you have an EU
passport, you can visit lots of
countries outside of the EU without a
visa at all. Uh so lot it opens a lot of
doors for you. Even in today's climate,
even in today's geopolitical climate, it
still opens a lot of doors for you.
Um so overall it's it's still
advantageous I would say in 20 years
time maybe the situation will change
significantly potentially possibly but
as of today um it's still very
advantageous
says Abijitra disagrees with the concept
of kill switches and fighter jets what
are your views on this I am very clear
I've said it very clearly
you can fighter jets are demonstrated to
have kill switches demonst demonstrated
I have given examples of this no I would
tell you slow forget about what people's
opinions are what my opinion is or what
Abijitra's opinion is or what somebody
else's opinion is forget about people's
opinions right why don't you do some
research of your own
why don't you do some research of your
own instead of asking me about my
opinion
figure out for yourself whether
this is a reality or not.
Now, let's so let me try and do some
spoon feeding to you all. Okay.
Um,
Australian fighter jets kill switch.
Okay. There is no physicala.
Okay. Let's ask this question.
Which American fighter jet did Australia
purchase in the 1980s?
Let's see.
Come on.
FA18 Hornet.
Okay. FA18 Hornets.
Now,
um, Australian FA18 Hornets.
Australian
FA18 Hornets.
Uh, 1980s
issues. Let's see what it says. There
were no issues. Initial design
deficiencies.
Uh D concerns with immaturity. It won't
tell you. It won't tell you. It won't
tell you.
Uh target 1980s
target acquisition
acquisition system.
Let's see what that says. Let's say
let's see. Let's see. Let's see.
H radar issues
scenarios warso backed.
See, look at this.
So now it's it's beginning to throw up
some issues. The radar warning receiver
limitation. The systems were initially
programmed for scenarios against
Warsofact forces. They were not
configured to detect radar emissions
from US or other Western aircraft
operation operating in Southeast Asia,
which limited the ability to identify
potential hostiles in the region. My
point is this.
See the radar,
the target acquisition system,
if you have purchased a fighter plane, h
then you should be able
to make it lock on to any target you
want.
Yeah, you should be able to make it lock
onto any target you want.
So I am flying my fighter plane. I see
I'm just doing it as an academic
exercise for for practice. I don't have
an actual missiles but I want to lock on
to so and so ship I see there or I want
to lock on to that aircraft that is
flying around there. Let me try and lock
on. It won't allow you to.
So the American aircraft FA18 aircraft
they did not allow the Australian pilots
and the Australian Air Force to lock on
to targets the Americans did not
approve. And when the Australians tried
to change the system, they were not
allowed to change the system. The
Americans did not share the source codes
of the software. That's what the French
are doing to India.
That's one example of a disabled
partially disabled aircraft there which
2019 or something
Israel has. Okay, let's let's see this.
Okay. Uh
Aaraijan Israeli systems failed.
Let's see. Let's see what it says. Oh,
really?
Uh no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Uh give me a second.
See, these things are deliberately
hidden from you. Okay, just give me a
second. I'm going to search for
something here. Okay. I'm going to
search for something here.
Uh here. Okay. Where where do we have
it? Let's see.
Ah 2014. Let's see now.
Um
2014 Azerbai Azarbaijan Israeli
manufactured UAVs failed to launch.
Let's see what do you have what we find
here now.
There is no credible information.
Oh well well
let's see let's see see the they're
going to they're going to hide this
information for you.
So all I can do if you want I can write
a detailed article finding all the
actual information and sources because
these sources are going to be hidden
from you. Uh the world doesn't want you
to want you to know about this recently.
Okay, let me try and find some more
actual uh verified information for you.
Let me see. Okay,
let me do that. Uh so let me go to my
Twitter account. I had found something
somewhere.
Um, my Twitter account. Let's search for
Let's search for 35.
Let's search for 35. What do we get?
D 35. 35. 35.
Uh,
okay. There's so many tweets here.
Let me see.
Um,
there have been admissions in the past,
in the recent past, that the F-35 has
kill switches.
But I'm going to have to dig it out from
wherever it is.
I'm going to have to dig it out.
Not this,
not that, not that, not that, not that.
Um,
so if you want to be spoonfed, you're
going to have to be a little patient.
Fake news unclear,
right? It was a couple of months ago and
there's so many tweets in between.
Okay. So, um this may take time.
Let me try for a couple of
seconds more.
Looks like it'll be difficult for me to
dig it out.
Where is that?
Where is it? Um
yeah. Okay. So, I'm I'm not going to do
that. My point is there is evidence. Uh
if I want to spoon feed you all, I'm
going to have to dig it out and it'll
take time. But I stand by what I say.
Kill switches, back doors, all of these
things exist.
I think anybody
who is very intelligent knows this.
Abijitra is a very intelligent person. I
have the highest amount of respect for
his intellect. Okay.
So
I stand by what I what I have said
multiple times and now you have NATO
nations corroborating what I'm saying
also. Okay, you just have to find it.
You need to have the patience to find
the information. So my point to you and
everybody else is to hell with my
opinion or his opinion or somebody
else's opinion. Why do you care what
someone's opinion is? Search for the
information yourself, right? And find
out, figure out for yourself whether
it's true or not. The information is all
out there in the public domain but it's
hidden away. You have to know how to
search for it. So please learn how to
search for information yourselves
instead of relying on someone's
opinions.
Uh Noman Ratnani thank you very much
Noman G
Pratip Kumar Roy says what's a stage
three nuclear reactor? A stage three
nuclear reactor is a reactor that uses
uranium 233 and thorium to produce uh
nuclear power.
Okay. And India has the world's largest
reserves of thorium which means that it
gives is going to once we reach stage
three it's going to give us essentially
limitless
power.
Hot potato says because of oil shortage
global economy suffers but US suffers
the least. Relative US gain weakens
China boosts dollar
assets demand. Thoughts?
Uh yeah I agree with you. I've said this
multiple times. I've spoken about this
in great detail.
Because of the oil shortage, the glo
global economy suffers and there's a
demand for oil. Because the straight of
hormones, it's not giving up giving out
the oil that it the world needs. It's
the world's most important energy choke
point. Straight of hormones. The US is
the world's largest producer of oil at
least on paper.
So if this situation continues for a
long time, the world and and the
Ukrainians on the behest of on the
behalf of the US start you know
degrading Russia's ports and so on that
are used for exporting oil then the
world will start will have to start
relying on American oil which
strengthens the petro dollar system
which weakens China which boosts the
demand for dollars and so on. Very
clear. Very clear right
Priya. Thank you very much. Pi Priya G.
Thank you very much ma'am.
Uh WYBKD says some people claim
professor Jang is Ankit Sha of the hand
race. I have no idea. No idea. I shall
not comment about various specific
people in any way whatsoever. Uh I think
professor Jam Jang whomever I seen seems
to be a very intelligent person. Uh I
don't watch his videos so I don't know
what he says but uh yeah. Okay. Rishies
dish Pande says do you believe the US
can have control over smartphone
companies like Apple, Google through
which they can attack any nation by
launching a cyber attack? How to stay
safe in the situation?
These smartphone companies Apple, Google
etc are American companies.
All American companies are geopolitical
assets.
Okay. If you are an a person of any
importance and if you have an Apple
product
they're listening to you in real time
it's a fact you have to leave live with
if so you see there are two major
operating systems one is Apple the other
one is IO one is iOS Apple's thing the
other one is Android now most of these
Android companies are either Chinese or
American if you have a Chinese phone the
Chinese will take your data and listen
to you if If you have an American
Android phone, the the Americans are
going to listen to you, right? You can't
launch cyber attacks, but you can do all
kinds of stuff, you know, like like
essentially siphoning off all the the
personal data of a of a person. So if
let's say hypothetically 70% of India's
phones the the phones that Indians own
um are of American origin let's say then
the data of 70% of Indians resides in
the hands of the US all your patterns
they understand you better than you
so they won't launch a cyber attack a
cyber attack is a one-time thing what's
the point of cyber attacks the more
important thing is to actually
understand the nation, understand the
patterns, consumption patterns, movement
patterns, all the patterns that is much
more viable and much more valuable than
launching a cyber attack. So the
solution to this, how to stay safe from
all these things is for India to have
its own cell phone brands, to have its
own highquality cell phone models.
Now you will say that you know some of
these cell phone brands are South Korean
brands, Samsung and
Huawei. No, it's Chinese. At least some
of these are South Korean, right?
Samsung, but Samsung, I mean, South
Korea is controlled by the US. It's a US
vasal. So, once again, it's US. Okay,
please. So, somebody's going to ask that
question. But you said America, but
South Korea is also there. South Korea
is a US asset. It's a US vasal. It's
controlled and owned by the United
States. So, how do you stay safe in the
situation? The only solution is for
India to become a major manufacturer of
indigenous cell phones. But India
doesn't bother to do that, right? So
here we are. Pratitumar Royce says,
"Your views about the freight
equalization policy of 1952 by NU
government major reason for the downfall
of Bengal. Maybe I don't know. I have
not studied this. So I can't say I don't
know everything in the world. I have not
studied the freight equalization policy.
I have heard about it but I haven't
studied it. So I shall refrain from
commenting."
Uh as KC says likely US now declining
like the UK during Suez 1953. Su was
56 56 58 whichever year it was Sue
crisis 195 what
56 or 58 it was also
seiz crisis year
come on 56 yeah so it was 1956 that the
sew crisis happened okay um and the
sewish crisis was this stamp of the
final downfall of the UK as a major
world power.
It
made it official that the UK was now a
second rate world power maybe and it it
now is a third rate world power.
So Suez was that kind of thing for the
UK. It made it very clear to the world
that the US is the top dog and the US in
the UK is a subsidiary nation that takes
orders from the US and has to obey
American dictates. That was 1956 for the
UK.
Okay.
Now 2026,
this war against Iran that the Americans
are waging right now, the US is
declining very clearly. The US no longer
has the ability to project power and
destroy countries, especially Iran.
It still can do it to other countries.
Okay? The US still can do it to other
countries, but it can't do it to Iran.
So, Iran has shown the world how to
inflict a strategic defeat on the United
States.
But the US isn't declining the way the
UK declined in 1956. The UK, the US
still has hundreds of military bases
across the world.
It still occupies so many countries.
So it's not declining the way the UK
declined in 1956. In 1956, UK went from
here to all the way down here. Went from
here to here. Here like big big fall
from here to here. There's a big fall
for the UK. Straight down.
For the US, it's it's it's it's more
gradual. The US is slowly declining.
It's it's nothing like the UK in 1956,
but the decline is still is still there.
It's visible now. When I recalculate the
hard part of the US, it's going to have
decreased. It It's going to have
decreased.
Okay. Roman Gil says, "Smart Dust
DARPA/Rand
Corporation 1992 MEMS project finished
in 2022. Potential use in chemtrails
with 6G interface thoughts. I have no
idea, but let me look it up."
Um, okay.
Smart dust DARPA.
What is that?
DARPA funded smart dust refers to
minuscule subm wireless micro
electrochemical electromechanical
systems. Sensors known as modes modes in
God's eye. Okay, that's different.
Sensors known as modes designed to
monitor data like light, temperature,
and vibration.
So, yeah, that's that's definitely a
viable technology. Yeah. uh microscopic
micro electromechanical systems. So
these are like tiny robots essentially
or tiny u sensors tiny sensors
um potential use in chemtrails
uh originally funed funded to enable
massive distributed sensing for and
eventually military environmental and
industrial monitoring. tiny sensors that
combine micro electro mechanical
systems, power source and wireless
communication. They can detect
environmental conditions including
light, magnetism, acceleration and
humidity. So this became projects like
neural dust which focuses on millimeter
scale wireless implants for monitoring
nerve activity in the body. Yeah, they
they may implant this within a person
without the person even knowing about
this potentially uh power management,
high energy density, etc. turbulence
uh precision
agriculture etc. Now, what about a
chemtrails?
Chemtrails.
Idiot. And what was it? 6G. 6G.
Good God. What's wrong with this thing?
Okay, let's see now what it says.
It'll say it's all conspiracy theories.
Uh chemtrails, chemical mapping,
conspiracy theory context. There you
have it. There you have it. Conspiracy
theory.
Um 6G network black backbone future
wireless networks.
Okay. So, so um what are my thoughts?
So, this this technology does exist. It
was started in 1992. It will have been
taken to the next level and next level
of that by now. Uh it's definitely a
viable technology. I'm sure you can
implant that that dust into people's
bodies without them even knowing about
this. Right. Uh 6G technology whenever
it comes about will definitely augment
the capabilities of the MEMS project.
Yes, definitely. Chemtrails I have no
idea. I've not studied chemtrails and as
you can see the Google AI say it's it's
conspiracy theories. But overall
what are my thoughts? My thoughts are
that there are these these technologies
that exist today that nobody is aware
of. There are all kinds of very advanced
uh secret technologies that DARPA and
Rand Corporation not Rand Corporation
but DARPA will have developed. Rand
Corporation is a think tank. It proposes
projects and ideas and then it is
organizations like DARPA etc that take
it up and what DARPA does is mostly
secret. So there will be technologies in
existence today that are like 20 30
years ahead of anything you can imagine
and they'll be deployed in the real
world.
So that is is a certainty and something
like smart dust can be very very useful
for whoever owns and operates the
technology for for the purposes of
surveillance and infiltration and god
knows what more spying etc.
Suri Chawan Suri Chawan says, "Thank you
for your val valuable live streams.
Because of you, I've started analyzing
news from different perspectives. Now I
surprise people by building a
constructive argument. Thank you once
again. Thank you so very much so very
much ma'am. I really appreciate your
very kind words." Thank you so much.
Suri G.
Aries Manticor says, "Operation Synindur
could be turned into a lone moving
operation. As you said, war keeps a
civilization young rather aligning
everyone together and creating the
effect of unity across society for
someone for some time.
Lawnmoving operation means you keep on
yeah the Israelis do lawnmowing right
that sort of thing. You see
theoretically you can turn operation
tendur into an ongoing project. But in
the real world, Pakistan is supported by
the United States.
And the US is way more capable and way
more powerful than India. They have
received a very very very nasty surprise
at the hands of the Iranians. And the
Iranians are almost too strong for the
US regionally in West Asia. But India
doesn't have Iran's capabilities.
India doesn't have a 100,000 drones and
tens of thousands of ballistic missiles
and cruise missiles,
right? And if you try to go to war
against Pakistan and start and turn it
into a lone moving operation, the
Americans will get involved in in
multiple ways and they'll make life very
difficult for you. They will even impose
sanctions on your economy which will
destroy your nation's economy and GDP.
Do you want that?
Hm.
India doesn't want to be involved or be
be embroiled in any major military
activity or operation for 20 years
because we want to grow our economy and
become a middle- inome nation
because that's what the people of India
want. The people of India are super
soft, very demanding. They want all
kinds of comforts and whatnot. All kinds
of, you know, they have all kinds of
complaints.
So if India gets embroiled in a war, it
can have multiple effects. If the
Americans decide to crush India's
economy, they can do it. And understand
one thing, my dear Indians, India is not
sovereign
from an energy perspective. We are not
energgetitically self-sufficient.
If the Americans decide to blockade
India and cut off India's imports of
oil, what are you going to be able to
do?
The US can do that if you if they want.
So then you'll be at war. Everyone will
be fighting. Your civilization will be
young but your e economy will be
crushed.
So India needs to find energy sources of
its own that it it owns entirely and can
defend. So until we do these things, we
should stay out of war essentially.
That's that's my point.
Beckenbower says namaskarum. Yes. Uh,
France wins by using overseas talent
from Africa.
Oh, you mean sports? I mean, if you look
at the French football team, it's more
like an African Union football team,
isn't it? Now, it is. It's a fact. It's
a fact. Okay, I'm not being racist or
whatever. It's a fact. Most of the
French football teams players are of
African origin today. We have a few who
are French.
Is one. And who else do we have French?
was fully French like ethnically French
was one zidad was north African
whatever okay so France wins by using
utilizing overseas talent from Africa
why can't Indian football use
highquality foreign trained OCI players
to build a world-class squad for future
world cups
we can explore the options but first of
all the Indian football association is
it even interested in
uplifting uplifting uplifting the
standards of football in India. We have
so much money in India.
But India is what? Ranked what in the
world in football? Maybe 100, maybe 90.
India's global football rank.
What is it?
Oh my goodness. The Indian football team
is ranked 136th in the world.
At least we should be in the top 50,
right? If we are not in the top 50, it
means the Indian football association
doesn't even even care about Indian
football. And I wonder what is the
objective of even having a football
association that does nothing.
After all these years in the 21st
century with all the money India has, we
can hire the most expensive coaches
today if we want, but we don't do it. It
means this the Indian football
association looks like it doesn't give a
damn about improving the the quality of
football in India
right so when you can clearly see the
Indian football association doesn't care
do you think they will do all these
things
you know highly high quality foreign
trained overseas citizen of India
players we should do it
why doesn't India have a football league
like the IPL even the IPL Well, actually
it's not the best league in the world
despite it being the richest league in
the world in terms of cricket. A a
serious professional league,
it operates for 8 to 9 months of a year.
Not it's not a two-month circus.
A professional serious professional
league should operate 8 or 9 months of a
year. It should not be a two-month
circus. So India has this football super
league or something. I don't know what's
going on in that when the the thing
started it was a good idea. I I even
watched some matches the the first year
you had the Indian football super league
or whatever it is called these days.
So if you have a highquality uh football
league in a country like India
which operates eight or nine months a
year and every year the standards
improve then in a decade or so India is
going to attract the best football
talent in the world. The Chinese have
done that. The Koreans have done that.
The Korean league, the Chinese league,
the Japanese league. That's how China
Japan China still isn't a great football
nation. But Japan qualifies for World
Cup. South Korea also does that. Even
North Korea does sometimes.
So it's it's about the fact that the
Indian football association is not doing
what it is supposed to do.
And secondly, the Indian government also
doesn't seem to be very interested in
sports. The sports is something that is
very important for a nation. It brings
the nation together whenever you win.
The best way to unify a nation is
through success in various domains.
So what you're suggesting makes a lot of
sense.
And why is this not happening? Well, you
have to ask the Football Association of
India. Why is it not happening? Why is
why isn't there a worldclass IPL quality
better than IPL quality global EPL
quality football league in India? Why
not?
Why don't we have it? We have the
resources. We have the money. You can
have these franchise teams just like in
in the EPL. These are all privately
owned teams. You have plenty of wealthy
private people in India.
Why can't it happen? There's something
wrong fundamentally in India.
These sporting associations are doing,
they are not doing what they're supposed
to do. And I wonder how the funds are
being managed and so on. That's the
biggest question. I'm just wondering.
I'm not saying anything. I'm just
wondering what's happening.
Rahman Priit says, uh, I want to know
what will be the long-term impacts of
this war of this war on Canada and how
do you see Canada as a country on the
world stage? Okay, let me answer the
second question first. How do I see
Canada as a country on the world stage?
I see Canada as a non- entity, as a
geopolitically insignificant nation and
I see Canada as a non-s sovereign
nation. I see Canada as a US vasal.
Canada essentially is owned by the
United States. It's not a real nation.
It's it's an artificial nation.
Canada doesn't have any actual culture,
any any any culture that binds the
people together,
right? And it's not a sovereign nation.
It's an extension of the US. It is a de
facto 51st state of the US.
It's like a USowned territory.
The US tolerates the Canadian system
that they have prime ministers who come
and go and no Canadian prime minister
actually matters at all in any way
whatsoever. Most of them are a joke like
you had the Mutau
who was an absolute joke.
Right? So Canada is
is a known entity on the world stage.
Its importance is that it's one of the
it's it's a huge territory which means
it has huge amounts of resources of
various kinds. Uranium
good uranium, good quantities of
uranium, oil, shale oil etc.
and other kinds of oil also I suppose
uh lumber so Canada has natural
resources which makes it important from
a resource perspective which is why it's
important for the US to control Canada
it does
right and on the world stage Canada is
is increasingly become a nuisance for
India of late through its espousal of
the Kalistthani uh separatists
right in Canadian territory
and they tolerate everything the
Kalistpanis do.
So that that that's why Canada has
become a nuisance for India. I mean the
worst terrorist attack that the that
Canada has suffered was done by
Kalistthanis. The Kaneska bombing and
what has Canada do about done about it?
Nothing nothing whatsoever.
So overall Canada is a nuisance for
India and overall on the global stage it
is a non- entity. It doesn't really
matter. It's it's a US-owned entity.
Now, what are going to be the long-term
impacts of this war on Canada? Nothing
much.
Overall, the the world's economy is
going to suffer as a consequence of the
war, but it may have a good effect on
Canada because Canada is a major oil
exporter. Uh what is Canada's ranking on
in the oil exporters league?
Uh what how does Canada rank in the
global oil exporting nations? What is
Canada's rank?
uh fourth position
you see Canada is a major massive
producer of oil Canada supplies over 60%
of US crude imports and holds the
world's fourth largest proven oil
reserves
right so Canada is a see if if if
Horus is impacted if Russia's oil
exports are impacted by because of
Ukrainian military activities then
Canada's importance is going to grow
significantly.
So overall it's going to be good for
Canada and for the US. Apart from that I
don't see much of a bad impact for
Canada sitting on the other side of the
planet. It it's going to be okay for
Canada. Now VK says how are you? I'm
good sir. How are you doing? I hope
you're doing great. What is the
significance of India's nuclear reactor
attaining criticality and its role in
energy security and defense in the
current geopolitical context? So I
explained this maybe I can explain it
all over again if you feel like and I
shall refer to my own tweet to explain
what the deal is because I have put
everything succinctly in one place in
that tweet. What is the significance of
of of India's U reactor one reactor
attaining Pritiki Khal? Let me give you
a
brief um overview of what's happened.
Okay. Uh so here we have my tweet and
check check out my tweet.
So the the prime minister of India
tweeted that today India has taken a
defining step in its civil nuclear
journey advancing the second stage of
the nuclear program the indigenously
designed and built prototype fast
builder reactor at Kalapakam has
attained criticality and so on. So I
have said that this is the landmark
moment India has now officially begun
its transition its entry into stage two
of Dr. Homi J Baba's three-stage nuclear
program. Okay. So our phase 2 is now
mature and complete. It is still
operation of phase one. Phase one our
phase one is now mature. It is complete.
It is still operating. And this new
reactor is our first stage to reactor.
First ever stage to reactor. We are now
officially
beginning the initial stage of phase
two.
Okay. And we have a long long way to go
because stage two reactors are going to
breed
additional fuel. Stage 2 reactors
produce more fuel than they burn. And
that fuel that we seek is uranium 233.
Okay.
So uranium 233 is going to be used in
the stage 3 along with thorium. Without
uranium 233, stage 3 doesn't happen. So
that's why we need stage 2 reactors to
breed large quantities of uranium 233.
So right now we are entering stage two.
It's our first reactor in stage two.
We're going to see how it performs.
Right now it's only generating heat.
It's only generating electricity. Then
we're going to put a thorium blanket on
this stage 2 reactor and we're going to
see how at at what rate does it start
breeding uranium 233. We're going to
have to test it, observe it, do various
experiments with it and find out what is
the optimal you know configuration of
the blanket and what is the highest
speed or rate at which it's able to
breed uranium 22 233.
Then after a couple of years, 2, three
years, we will have some understanding
of how what is the best way to operate
this reactor. Then we'll build one more
and then we'll see how that works. So
then we have two working reactors. After
let's say uh 10 years from today, then
we build five more.
That takes another 10 years. So 20 years
from now, let's say we have seven of
these pressurized fast reactors ideally
hopefully. Then in 30 years we may have
20 if we don't become lazy.
Then in 50 years we may have enough
uranium 233 to start sta to start stage
three. And it's in stage three that we
have to again start testing with one
prototype reactor.
Test it. How does it work? And in stage
three we use uranium 233 and thorium. We
have the world's largest thorium
reserves. But to
use those
reserves, we have to enter stage three,
which may be 40, 50 years down the line,
at least 30 years down the line.
Then we can start testing the stage
three reactors
and that may take a few years. It's only
when we have like 30 40 stage three
reactors that we will have large
quantities of energy that this will
start producing for the country. Ideally
eventually we will want to have a 100
200 stage three reactors that may be 70
years down the line perhaps that's when
we have unlimited energy because of the
huge quantities of thorium that we have
all right it's a long story it's a long
way to go for us let's be patient all
right
says I don't want us to even step into
this conflict as mediators even if they
want us either party is likely to break
any terms. This is a fight of an impass.
It's not our place to fiddle around. I
would say I agree with you completely
like like I've said, I've said that
India should not be involved in any of
these mediation processes. It's not our
war.
It's not our war. We don't want to get
tangled in these matters in this fight
between two implacable adversaries.
Okay? Especially the Americans who are
not fighting fair. There is no sense of
fighting fair with them.
They don't have any sense of any any
desire to fight fair. This is not
supposed to be a this is not meant to be
a fair fight. That's what Mr. Hexath
said, didn't he? We don't want to be
involved in this matter at all. Let us
stay out of it. The Americans and
Israelis started the war. Let them end
it or and let them use Pakistan if they
want. We should stay out of it. Okay? We
should stay as far as possible away from
this conflict. So I completely agree
with you.
Matabish says India at nuclear stage two
real big deal this decade after moon
landing hardly getting any traction
globally although as good geopolitical
impact as current war undervalued
deliberate inconsequential
look this is something most people don't
understand okay
um it's a big deal that we have now
finally entered stage two but we may be
30 40 years away from stage three also
understand that and this government
future governments will have to ensure
sure that the program continues as fast
as possible without going too fast that
so so that nothing breaks.
So we're going to have to invest
sufficient amounts of money in the
nuclear program not treat the nuclear
program the way we are treating our
space space program right now. So it's
important it's definitely important.
Okay. Ideally we should have been
halfway through stage two by now. We
have been very lax, very lazy, very
unambitious so far. We should have
completed stage two by the end of the
20th century actually. Okay, we have
been very slow at this matter. Past
governments have not taken the nuclear
program seriously.
But thankfully we still have about 22 or
something nuclear reactors. And this
one, the new Kalapakam one is is the
next generation reactor, stage two
reactor. So we need to study how it
operates, how it how it functions. We
have to test with various parameters,
various configurations, various
configurations of the of the thorium
blanket whenever we bring it in
and eventually we build a second one
based on what we learned from the first
one. So whether we have then we have two
reactors working then we learn the
lessons of the second reactor. Then we
build five more. Then we learn the
lessons of the five to of the seven
first seven reactors. We build 10 more
and so on. So iteratively we make it
better and eventually we have a fleet of
let's say 50 stage two reactors in 40
years time perhaps and then we need
those reactors to to keep running for
years and years and years so that we
start accumulating sufficient amounts
maybe tons of uranium 233.
Then with the first batch of uranium 233
we can start the stage three reactor.
There also you have to design properly.
It takes time to design all it and plan
it and implement it. So it's a long long
process. Okay. And globally why should
it get traction? The whole world wants
India to fail.
So no one wants to talk about this
globally that India has achieved this
incredible thing that the Americans
couldn't achieve. Right? So globally
it's not going to get too much traction
but at least locally domestically in
India it should get traction but most
people don't understand what this is all
about. That's why yeah Krishant the
Bordo says have you watched the movie
yet? I still haven't watched it.
Maybe I should go and watch it tomorrow.
I know Durander 2, right? I still
haven't watched it, but I will of course
watch it. Uh when it comes to Durander
one, I watched it after a month and a
half it was released. When all the hype
was all over the place and then hype
started dying down, that's when I went
and watched it peacefully in a theater
with not packed with people. Uh maybe
I'll go and watch it tomorrow. Let's
see.
But eventually I certainly will watch
it. Even if I don't watch it tomorrow, I
look forward to it. Prattana says,
"Assuming I'm sure Harapans are Vic
people. I am certain they are our
ancestors, the Vic people. 100%
certain." So, does the second tire,
upper city, lower city hypothetically
indicate two classes, rulers, elites and
common citizens? No. I've seen no
evidence of two tires, two two classes
of people in um so-called harapen
cities.
uh upper two-tier upper city lower city
where do you see that you don't see that
in Kalibangan you don't see that in
Rakari you don't see that in Mojaro
do you see that in Harapa no in Harapa
and Mohen Mojudo there are certain u
constructions or buildings that are
pretty large those are public works like
a meeting house or or or or
the great bath they say or whatever it
is right and then there are standard
houses which are for regular
uh so the public works are going to be
larger because you want big assemblies
of people who can be accommodated within
those buildings. So that obviously makes
sense but I have not seen any any such
classification of of two different tiers
of
buildings in the in the various cities.
The buildings on the cities all look the
same essentially they look very similar.
It's not like the you see no evidence of
there being more lavish, more grandiose
buildings and then buildings that are
more modest. You don't see that at all.
Right? So I don't I have not seen any
evidence of this. Okay. Aon says a Aon
says why is it that that we are friend
to all but do not have that much of an
influence to do what we want and stop
wars maybe or stand up and condemn the
US. Why should we stand up and condemn
the US the most powerful nation in the
world? We don't want to do that. Why
should we go and stop wars which we did
not start?
Why is it our business to stop wars?
To stop a war, you have to go and spend
time, effort, money, energy. Why should
we do it? Why?
And why should we condemn the US
when it is the most powerful nation in
the world? It's like you go into the
lion's den and shout at the lion that
you are bad. Why do that?
Instead of doing all this verbal
nonsense, we should shut the hell up and
ourselves become a lion. That's what we
should do. And that's why we are friend
to all. Whoever wants to work with us
constructively, we'll work with them so
that we can benefit from everybody and
they can also benefit from us.
That's why we are friend to all. What we
seek to do is not to be the person who
is little but shouts at everybody and
points fingers in their face. No, we
want to stay quiet and we want to become
the next lion.
Okay, that's what we're trying to do.
Forget about influence. We don't want
influence. We want power. Influence is
overrated. Power is what you want.
So that's what India should do to hell
with be be with standing up and
condemning the bullies to hell with
stopping wars that we haven't started.
We will simply mind our business and be
selfish as all nations are. Finally, we
are waking up to these things slowly.
some of us at least.
Vinodov says, "Why are Iranians and
Hindus often so self-correcting,
philosophical, hopeful about people and
world despite being betrayed or taken
advantage of historically?"
Well, there are lots of traits that are
common to Iranians and Indians, Iranians
and Hindus, right? Persians and Hindus
because we have the same origin.
Uh the Persian and the Hindu people have
the same origin.
Our ancestors back in the day like 3 4
thousand years ago were the same. We all
have common ancestors, right? And we had
a common shared culture which event
which eventually Persia lost because of
unfortunate circumstances. The Rashidun
Caliphate invasion and occupation of
Persia
680 AD or whichever year it was I forget
doesn't matter.
So um so so India and Persia started
drifting apart after the Rashidon
invasion and occupation of Persia and
the forcible conversion of the majority
of the population to to their religion
the religion of the Arabs Islam right
but even if your religion changes your
deeper cultural traits persist
so Persia is an old civilization 3,000
years old before the Akameid dynasty you
had the Median dynasty and so
And the origins are the same for us and
the Persians. And we are an even older
civilization,
right? 10,000 years. And that's where
Persia's roots also lie with us. So
there are a lot of similarities between
us and the Persians. Similar
cultural traits, civil similar
civilizational civilizational traits,
shared ethnic origins, all of that. So
you're going to have a lot of
similarities and whatever drawbacks you
have, you know, whatever flaws and
drawbacks Indians have, you're going to
see a lot of that inong among the
Persians too. Yeah. So yeah,
you know, we tend to see the world
not through the lens of, you know,
um that we should be predatory on the
world. we should ex be extractive from
the world not we haven't we don't see
the world that way right we we Indians
think of the world in in an idealistic
way
the world is not one family we should
all live and let be we should all get
along together the Persians also kind of
see the world in that way
and historically
they did see the world that way
so yeah because of these shared traits
uh we kind of you know
get betrayed from time to time and we
are taken advantage of from time to time
and I think we should
you know together learn the lessons of
history India and Persia right
says how important is risk and
discomfort in individual life discomfort
is important because it keeps you it
keeps you discomfort is a good
motivation to improve your standards
Right? If you're not comfortable, if
you're not happy, you want to be out of
whatever situation is exists that makes
you uncomfortable, that's motivation to
to stay to keep moving and to keep
improving. So that's important.
Discomfort is important and discomfort
is the antidote to complacency,
right? So discomfort is important. Risk
is also important because risk does
bring you discomfort, but risk has to be
managed properly. You have to learn risk
management. You can't take ridiculous
risks
that that can be very counterproductive.
So risk has to be managed properly. You
have to understand what risk is. You
have to understand how to manage it. You
can take risks but you take calculated
risks and be if you take a calculated
risk, you have to be genuinely willing
to deal with the consequences if things
don't go well.
So yeah, that's the relevance of risk
and discomfort in individual life. Uh my
views on Greenland and future trade
routes in the Arctics. Greenland is a
fantastic piece of ice. Uh Denmark owns
it. The Americans occupy it. There's a
tremendous amount of resources on the
territory apparently. But it's covered
under kilometer or two of ice which is
fine. We can you know if with technology
can deal with it. And Denmark is a uh
Greenland is a strategically important
location. So let's open the map and take
a look at Greenland. Right. Greenland
where does it sit? Why is it
strategically important? Um, see
Greenland,
it sits between Russia and North
America. So if the Americans said that
Russia is evil and it'll launch missiles
someday, right? So if the Russians
hypothetically launch missile missiles
in North America, if you are in
Greenland, you will be the first to see
those missiles. So that's why Greenland
is important. If the Russians want to
dominate the Arctic region, if you own
Greenland, then you can prevent the
Russians from taking over the whole
region. So Greenland is valuable from
multiple perspectives. Okay, in the map,
Greenland looks like it sits between
Sweden and and and Canada, but actually
it sits between Russia and North
America. If you look at it from this
perspective, look here. See, Grinland is
between Russia and North America. Very
important place strategically. And if
you own the place, it will be you can
make it difficult for the Russians to
navigate the region. So, it's like a
geographical choke point. It's it's one
of a set of choke point in the region.
So, very important overall. And if the
Arctics start thawing and they are more
navigable for more months of the year
then Greenland becomes even more
important. Yeah. All right. Uh Pratip
Kumar Roy Iran versus India.
Hypothetically who would win? Well, we
have nukes. They don't see
hypothetically. Okay, we can talk about
this in the real world. We never want to
fight Iran. Why should we fight Iran?
Our cousins. Why should we fight our
cousins?
There was a time when they were our
brothers. There was a time when we were
the same people. Today we are cousins.
We are blood cousins. Okay. India and
Iran. Why should we fight them? What has
Iran ever done to us? Okay. You will say
Nadesha. Nadesha was a godamned bloody
Turk.
He was a Turk. He was not Persian. He
was like Orurange for Iran. Orang was a
Turk who ruled over India. Nadasha was a
Turk who ruled over Iran.
That's the only time Persia did
something bad to India. But there was
there was a Turk who did it right. But
historically when has Persia ever fought
India? They have always consciously
fought westwards. They've always
expanded westwards. They never ever
expanded eastwards east of the Indas of
the Cindu. Never. The Sindu was the
border between India and Persia
historically. And then the borders keep
shifting over time. That's fine. So
there is no reason for India and Persia
to ever ever ever fight no matter what
the religions are of the two countries.
But hypothetically if India and Persia
fight conventional war,
Persia has the overwhelming advantage.
Too many missiles, too many drones.
India doesn't have that.
Yeah. Um I don't know how many missiles
we have, but Persia has more. Quantity
has a quality of its own. And drones,
Persia has way too many drones for
India. But if you talk about the
non-conventional weapons, we have them.
The Persians don't. So there we have an
advantage. Air Force Air Force doesn't
matter today.
Missiles and drones matter. You if you
send an air force into a foreign
country, you're putting your pilots and
your valuable equipment equipment at
risk. The Iranians have been able to
shoot down American F-35s, American
F-15s,
American drones of various kinds.
Better not send your air force there. So
hypothetically conventional war Iran has
the advantage. Uh non-conventional war
obviously the Iranians don't have nukes.
So we have the advantage but we never
want to fight a non-conventional war.
You see Iran is a great power now. They
have proven that. But India Persia
should never ever fight. Why why should
we fight? There's no need for us to
fight. There's no reason for it.
Okay.
Iran says the way Jh Shankar says we
that we don't listen to anyone and yet
we sought American permission to resume
buying Russian oil. We had paused our
buying of Russian oil. Now we are buying
that oil at premium premium price. See
look we never actually stopped buying
Russian oil. We had uh slowed down
our purchases of Russian oil. We had uh
we we we we we had uh
if we were buying let's say a million
barrels per day hypothetically we had
like brought it down to maybe half of
that or something right so we had re we
had reduced our consumption of Russian
oil we hadn't ever stopped it completely
but we had reduced it because of the
American pressure yes
and then now we are buying that oil at a
premium price because the whole world
needs Russian oil it is what it is
earlier we buying it at at big
discounts. We spent four years buying
Russian oil at huge discounts. Then we
reduced our consumption. Now we have
increased it again because of no we have
no choice and now we are paying a
premium price. It is what it is. Uh and
we did get pressurized by the Americans
in a variety of ways.
It is
it is simply a fact of life that the
Americans are too powerful and they can
arm twist India in various ways. It is
simply a fact of life. It doesn't mean J
Shanka is a bad bad foreign minister. It
it only means that India is a weaker
country than the US. And no matter who
is your foreign minister,
if you think Jay Shanker isn't good
enough, somebody else has to be brought
in. Whoever you bring in as foreign
minister, the US will still be able to
arm twist India. So it's not J.
Shanker's fault or Modi's fault. It is
the fault of India's weakness, relative
weakness compared to the US. India is
not comparable in terms of hard power to
the US. Okay. Iran regionally can
overcome the US. I don't think India can
right now regionally. So India has to
work on these matters. Work on these
things.
Katos Aryan Shawwasi says Tajakistan
small 98% Muslim country but of proud
Persian roots rejects the RN invasion
theory step theory arguing for
indigenous continuity roots. But we
don't really I have no idea of what
Tajakistan thinks about this. There are
lots of people in Persia in Iran who
believe in the RN invasion theory.
So maybe I should reconnect with Porsche
and teach them some of what I have
discovered as with the evidence but
whatever. So I am not aware of what the
Tajik people believe about this. I was
under the impression that most Persian
people at least in Persia in Iran they
believe the RN invasion theory
but Tajakistan rejects this. That's
interesting. I will have to look into
it. That's that's complete news to me.
The first time I'm hearing this. The
Tajakistan the people of Tajakistan are
are of Persian ethnicity. They are not
Turks. The other stans like Kyrgystan,
Kazakhstan, Usbakistan,
etc. These are Turk nation.
Turkmanistan. These are Turk nation. The
people there are Turk people. They speak
Turk languages.
But Tajakistan is an is an Iranian
nation. The people are of Iranian
Persian origin and they speak Persian.
Um so they reject the invasion theory,
the step theory arguing for indigenous
continuity roots. We don't well we
should learn from the Tajjik have in
that case we should learn from the
Tajiks I really appreciate that and I
I'll check it out what the people of
Tajakistan believe in good I'm glad to
hear this thank you for letting me know
Ashish Gautam says India policy of
isolating Pakistan failing your
viewpoint my viewpoint is I am not
concerned about Pakistan
we are not isolating Pakistan we are
ignoring Pakistan we will not talk to
Pakistan we will not negotiate with
Pakistan we will not give Pakistan the
information the the importance of
bringing them to the same table as us
whether they isolated or not is not
important to us. We simply don't want to
have any kind of conversation or
dealings or dialogue or anything with
Pakistan and that's our policy. We are
not going out of our way to isolate
Pakistan. The Americans love Pakistan.
The Americans see Pakistan as a great
asset. So we can't isolate them but we
can ignore them and we can keep them out
of our dealings and that's what we are
doing and we are doing spectacularly
well at that. Okay.
Uh, Vinod says, "One leftist once
leftist guy drank and claims most of the
Hindus are emotional and have not don't
have great IQ. Fill them with moral
utopia, install guilt in them and
suddenly take out the problem in them.
Use words like democracy and secular."
Um,
okay.
Okay. So, is there a question? Is there
a statement? What what is what is it
that you want me to say about this? I
have no idea who is this who this
leftist guy is.
He drank he drank what? Alcohol.
Very bad. Very naughty. U most Hindus
are emotional. That's true. Most Hindus
are emotional. Most Indians are
emotional. Whether they're Hindus or
not.
Most Indians are emotional. Very
emotional people. Indians.
IQ or not, that is a different story.
I'll not go into that matter. Fill them
with moral utopia. Installed guilt.
Yeah. Yeah. Installed guilt works very
well with Indians. So lot of what these
people say actually is true right I
don't know certainly take out problem in
them democracy secular yeah so the the
root cause of all these problems in
India is the education system which
keeps Indians
dumb so we to fix the education system
but no politician will want to do it
because the politicians benefit from
Indians remaining dumb and stupid so
they will not change the education
system which means I will have to do
something about it on my
Okay.
Sujel Rajput says JD Vance going to
Pakistan to meet Iran to meet the
Iranian delegation or whatever. What
talks can happen? We'll see. We'll see
what happens. The Iranians seem to be a
very trusting people. They're still
going ahead with talks with JD Vance.
How can you trust the Americans? The
Americans are simply waiting for a
better opportunity to to to crush Iran.
In the meanwhile, they will do all these
these the this this you know they'll
make a big show of having negotiations
and all but at the end of the day
they're waiting for an opportunity to
kill you all.
So if this happens if the talks go ahead
then there will be talks. What will
happen? I don't see much happening as a
consequence of that. Maybe JD Vance will
convince the Iranians that yeah, I truly
want peace with Iran and maybe they will
make some big announcement
that yes, now we finally have a
ceasefire and maybe it'll last for a
week or so. Or maybe it'll last 15
minutes before Israel again breaks the
ceasefire. Who knows what will happen?
At the end of the day, big story, big
picture. The Americans and Israelis are
waiting for the opportunity, right time
and the right opportunity to crush Iran
completely. In the meanwhile they will
do all this negotiations and all that
makes no difference long long term.
Ratip Kumar Roy says your views about
the theory of evolution. It's the
correct theory. This is the absolutely
correct theory. I agree with the theory
of evolution. I do
Sunni says how to think any process to
make right decision. How to think
correctly? Well, that's
I can't tell you in a few minutes how to
think correctly. How to make the right
decisions.
You know understand decision- making for
that
and decision making it depends on what
what domain of decision you're trying to
make. Is it a financial decision? Is it
a strategic decision in business? It is
a is it a decision about what to do in
your personal life.
They're all different domains with
totally different decision-m skills and
and mental models and worldviews and all
that.
It's it's
how to make the right decision. It has
to be taught to you over multiple
multiple years as as a person who is
growing up. It's impossible to teach you
that in 5 minutes here,
right? You to learn mental models.
You to learn
you to learn probabilistic theory. You
you you can think of making decisions in
in terms of you know what if I bet this
much money on this or that much money on
that. I am not saying you should bet
money ever. I'm saying think in terms of
bets and probabilities.
Right? You have to use different
approaches for decision-m.
It's very hard to teach it in five
minutes. It's impossible to teach it in
five minutes. But yeah, you can make a
proper course on decision-m. You have to
think from a game theoristic game
theoretic game theoretic perspective.
Which is why I've said in the past
multiple times that if you want to learn
one skill that I I would recommend it
would be game theory. learn game theory,
basic game theory. Start with the p, you
know, prisoners dilemma and all that
basic stuff. You understand how
how decisions are made based on game
theory. So yeah, that's what I would
recommend. Start with that. Uh, Ban Bhan
Mikari says, "If the government of India
throws infinite rupees at S2,
can we get S3 critical in 10 years?" No,
not in 10 years. That's the problem. And
it's going to take time irrespective
because you have the first fast media
reactor that we have just
operationalized. It has just gone
critical which means it is now producing
a a nuclear reaction that is ongoing.
We are controlling the nuclear reaction.
We will have cadmium rods and whatnot
and we are controlling that and now
we're going to run it. We're going to
see what are the characteristics of the
nuclear reaction. what is the maximum
energy output that we can generate
safely.
Then we're going to put a thorium
blanket on it and we're going to see you
know what what kind of thorium blanket
gives you what kind of um breeding of
uranium 233. So we're going to have to
do multiple experiments over a period of
time on this reactor to understand how
to operate it optimally to generate
power and to breed uranium 233.
So after doing these experiments for
like let's say 2 three years we will
have a decent understanding of how this
kind of reactor works. Then based on the
lessons we learn on on this from this
reactor we're going to make a bigger
let's say fasted reactor and we're going
to then do all all the same process all
over again on the second one. Then based
on the lessons we learned on from the
first two reactors we may let's say
build a third batch of reactors maybe
three more. So that takes time. So after
15 years, you may have five fast breeder
reactors that are operational
and then you study the whole thing for
another few years. Then we build another
batch of five. Then after 20 25 years we
have got 10.
Then by this time your project your
program is mature. But now we understand
very well how these fast bid reactors
work. So after 20 25 years you build 10
more. So by 35 you may have
20 reactors.
In 30 30 let's say in 30 reactor 30
years ideally you have 20 reactors then
by 40 years you may have let's say 30 or
maybe even 40 reactors then let them
operate for another 5 years and you may
have sufficient uranium 233 to start
the first reactor of stage three. So no
matter how much money you spend you
throw at this stage two it's going to
take you time
and because these fast breed reactors
they will generate I don't know a few
kilograms of fuel at most per year. Let
me just ask Google Ive not done the
calculations how much fuel it generates
but let's see
how many grams of uranium 233 can
India's prototype fast breeder reactor
generate per year. Let's see if Google
has any answer. How many grams?
Um, it's designed to breed plutonium 239
production
233. What does it say? Yeah, all that is
fine. We want to convert, we want to
breed uranium 233. And it's not giving
you the answer.
Not publicly confirmed. Obviously, it's
just started.
Okay. So plutonium we can produce which
is fine but we actually are after the
uranium 233
right and that we don't know. So okay I
I may have to do some calculations to
actually understand how much it can do
based on various things. So it may be
able to produce a few kilograms of
uranium 233 per year and that is the
fuel we want to use in stage three and
we want to have at least a few tons of
that before we start start stage three.
No, it's going to take time. It's going
to take time.
Okay. Shubam says, "Do you think Bhutan
is a vasal of India?" We never speak of
Bhutan like this. We have the greatest
amount of respect for Bhutan. We have
the greatest amount of love for the
people of Bhutan. Bhutan is a brother
nation of India. Okay? And we cherish
our relationship with Bhutan and we
shall always take care of Bhutan and we
will ensure Bhutan's safety and
prosperity.
All right? That's that's how I see
Bhutan.
Okay. uh soldier boys's current vasahood
probability and chavda index. So I have
said in the past that India has a 50%
probability of becoming an American
vasal in the next 5 years.
What is the current vasal probability? I
would say it's dropped by at least 10%.
At least 10%. Chavda index I will have
to put it out in in a month or so
maximum. So this war right now is it
paused? Is it not? Has the ceasefire
collapsed? I don't know what's happening
right now but it's been a month that the
war is going on and I said that I'll
I'll reconstruct the index and
recalculate this course after the end of
the war. I don't see this war ending now
soon. So I will put this new index out
the 2026 index out within a month at mo
at most. Okay. And I should publish it
in a website. Um current probability has
come down by at least 10%. based on the
US the the American the abysmal American
performance in this war and that
obviously affects its hard power and its
ability to coersse nations like India.
Okay, Vinodov says Anglo claims China is
a paper tiger. Russia is a gas station
with nukes. India is just a market for
the US with a 100fold climbs we control.
We rule world we rule the world still
and continue to rule the world. I
suppose is that what you think? The US
sees the world in these terms. I agree.
They claim China as a paper tiger. But
what if China has a million drones that
they can launch at Taiwan? Is that a
paper tiger? That's not a paper tiger.
That's a frighteningly powerful nation.
The US is turning out to be a paper
tiger in West Asia right now. Thus far,
its performance has been that of a paper
tiger. China is no paper tiger.
If this is the effect the drones and
missiles have, then China, I promise
you, has way more drones and missiles
than Iran. And China, the Chinese are
not stupid. They are very keenly
watching what's happening in the war.
And they have already understood what it
takes to defeat the US. And they will
take what it takes to defeat the US and
multiply that by 10 or 20 or even 30.
That's what the Chinese do. China is no
paper tiger. If there's a war tomorrow
morning in Taiwan, the Chinese will
defeat the US.
Guaranteed.
So, China is no paper tiger. Russia is a
gas station with nukes.
Russia is more than a gas station with
nukes.
But the nukes are essential to Russia's
hard power. India is just a market for
us with 100fold lives control. More or
less. True. What does India produce that
the world needs? Tell me what does India
manufacture that the world needs?
What? What?
Right. India doesn't manufacture
anything the world needs in in great
numbers in great quantities.
India has a tremendous amount of fault
lines that we aren't working on. We
aren't solving. We aren't we aren't
fixing those fault lines. So when it
comes to India, the Americans are mostly
right.
Okay. Rahul Mahajan. Will Pakistan's
image improve because of this involve? I
have been speaking for the past 3 hours
that Pakistan's image has taken a big
hit because of what's happened. Their
image is going down. What improve
kar improved?
It's not improving. Pakistan has
backstabbed Iran. They've betrayed Iran.
Their claims have turned out to be
hollow. The Pakistani prime minister
said that Lebanon is included in in the
ceasefire and Israel then in 5 minutes
goes and bombs Lebanon. Where what is
Pakistan standing in the world after
that? Pakistan's word what value does it
have nothing right nothing
soldier boy says India's 5 to 10 year
outlook with the current system
5 to 10 years India will continue go
making like you know econom like growth
between five see 6 to 8% was supposed to
be but after the Iran war maybe it will
come down so we're going to keep on
going keep on going at a decent pace but
no major reforms are happening so India
will kind of in 10 years also be the
same kind of nation but with a larger
GDP somewhat larger GDP maybe 10% 20%
larger maybe maybe 50% larger GDP I
don't know what it is
but what you need is massive
transformative reforms right if you want
to truly unleash the potential of the of
the people and of the civilization that
is not happening so India is going to
keep on going at the at a linear growth
rate more or less the way things are
current system Abida Singh says did
Russia really tip How about Van Djke or
did we just want to catch him in West
Bengal? And can we use him as a tariff
discount once the Iran war is off? We
can't use him as a tariff discount. The
Americans will not give into any kind of
blackmail or arm twisting. Yeah, we
can't. Did Russia really tip us off?
Well, I don't know because I am not
involved in the RAW or in the
government. So, I have absolutely no
idea. There are many YouTubers who know
everything.
I have these I am I am a past member of
RAW. I know everything what's happening
in RAW. I have a direct hotline with a
DAL. There are many YouTubers who do
that. I have no connection with RAW and
I have no connection with the government
of India. Which is why I have no idea
whether Russia really tipped us off or
not about Van Dyke. If Van Dyke is in
India, why do we need Russia to tip us
off? He's in India, right? Why do we
need Russian help to understand what's
happening inside India? Are we that dumb
and stupid?
So let's not get ahead of ourselves and
imagine that Russia has helped us catch
a guy who is already in India and doing
nasty stuff.
Okay. Godliness says staying positive is
good but Indian state uh the Indian
state has to wake up. I fear for the
northeast now. Yeah, northeast is the
mess. Manipur is a disaster ongoing
disaster. All states in northeast now
have Anglo culture and that what is
happening in Manipur is the same in
Kashmir. I agree. What's happening in
Manipur is actually worse than Kashmir
in some ways.
Manipur
is under foreign occupation.
Yeah, you can now give those foreign
occupiers other cards and say they are
Indians but they are not Indian.
Even Bangladesh have other cards. I am
sure many Bangladesh have passports now,
Indian passports. Does it make them
Indian? India is under Bangladeshi
occupation and Manipur is under foreign
occupation.
at least half of Manipa. At least half.
It's a disaster,
right? So in in a lot of ways it's
similar to what happened in Kashmir.
It's happening right now.
Happening right now. Right now as as we
speak there's a reign of terror in
Manipur.
And why is this being tolerated by the
government of India is something I I
fail to understand.
So yes. Yes. problems.
Yeah.
Okay. Goat Ghost says, "Please see
Koochie fire missile.
Excuse me.
Ky fire missile in Made Civil Land."
What is Kusi? Okay, let me see what it
what it says. K U C I fire missile.
I don't know what's Kushi or Coochie or
whatever it is. What is that?
K U CI I'm sorry I'm not able to get
what you're saying sir. If you could be
a little more clear then I would be love
I would love to take a look at it. Okay.
Okay. Roshan Panei Panigra says UN
failed. The UN is long obsolete. US the
UN is long obsolete. Right. The UN
failed and the international
organizations are useless. Right-wing
parties are winning. Are we heading to
preWorld War political scenario impact
on trade? In some ways we are kind of in
a preWorld War I kind of scenario right
lots of yeah nations that are waiting
for an opportunity to to set things
right that sort of thing kind of the
situation kind of reminds you of the
preWorld Wars one scenario u little bit
impact on trade trade is going to be
impacted now the world is splitting up
into different blocks right you no
longer have a global trade system and
the energy crisis which is the result of
the current war against Iran, it's going
to have another impact on trade.
So, we are kind of like in some ways we
the situation today is in some ways
reminiscent of the preWorld War I
scenario. Uh the UN has obviously
failed, completely utterly failed. It's
completely irrelevant today. The United
Nations, international organizations are
useless. The Americans have rendered
them useless. Rightwing part is I don't
care right-wing, leftwing, who wins,
whoever is popular should win, that's
fine. uh impact on trade there there's
obviously going to be impact on trade so
overall it's a disrupted system that we
have right now it's a fracturing system
that we have now right we have multiple
we have essentially two big blocks is
one is the US-led western block the
other one is the China China Russia uh
Iran North Korea block and then you have
a bunch of global south nations like
which includes India India wants to be
in various places uh that sort of thing
and overall trade is impacted lots of
things are impacted
says your views on the new moon mission
by NASA. I think it's going well. Right.
Uh they are it's not a it's not a lunar
landing mission. It's a lunar uh orbit
mission. There's going they're going to
do one orbit of the moon, partial orbit
of the moon and then going to they're
going to return back to the earth and
it's going very well. I suppose the
images they they've sent back are pretty
spectacular. So I think it's a great
initiative by NASA. The Americans are
serious about going back to the moon,
about taking ownership of parts of the
moon and they're going to achieve it
soon. they're going to start the process
of achieving it soon. Yeah. So I think
great for the US and uh it makes me a
bit jealous because India has no
ambition similar to what the Americans
have. We have the resources, we have the
brains, the talent but we don't have the
ambition sadly.
Aeron says we are why are we dependent?
Why not build our own jets? Ask the
politicians. We should have been
building our own jets long long ago.
We had the Marut H Marut jet which was
one of the best fighter jets of the
1970s. It was underpowered because we
used the we used weak jet engines in
that but the fighter plane design was
brilliant
but our politicians killed it. They
decommissioned the fighter plane. If we
had not decommissioned it and if we had
iteratively improved upon it and you
know created offroot fighter planes from
it, we would have multiple fighter plane
families today which would have been top
of the class in the world and we could
have if we had started the jet engine
program in the 1960s
we would have had high quality jet jet
engines today. Even today we can go
forward with the carav jet engine
program. I think it's almost good enough
to become operational in in a fighter
jet fighter jet right
and u yeah so it's it's it's a question
of political will why we are where we
are right Pratip Kumar Roy says about
antimatter transport experiment I've
never heard of it no no such thing
exists antimatter transport experiment
that's something you will see in some
Philadelphia experiment movies and all
that no such thing has actually happened
as far as I Antimatter
is a real thing.
Okay. But antimatter transport
experiment. No, I I don't even need to
look it up. That's all
um that's all what they would call what
conspiracy theories. Sumit Kumar says,
"What are your unbiased sources of
information?" In fact, thank you for
your channel. I it's not like I have
like five five sources that I look to
look forward to that I that I rely on. I
look at every source of information
and all sources of information are
biased. All of them are biased.
Everybody is biased. The BBC is biased.
Syrian is biased. Chinese sources are
biased. German sources are biased.
Japanese sources are biased. Russian
sources are biased. Indian sources also
have their own biases. Every source is
biased. So you have to understand what
each source what is the bias of each
source.
And then based on everything and all the
sources you have to based on your own
understanding and wisdom and judgment
and experienced you have to try and
construct a picture of what's really
happening. That's how I do it. I don't
have any unbiased sources of
information. All sources of of of
information are biased and polluted.
Okay, that's the fact of the world.
There are no unbiased sources.
Podcast Punjabi says World War II. Did
the US help Germany backhand so UK fall?
I am not aware of that.
Did the US help Germany behind the
scenes so the UK falls? No. The US went
ahead and destroyed Germany with the
help of the UK.
So there was no behindthe-scenes help
that the Americans gave to Germany
during World War II. No, they first went
ahead and defeated Germany.
Okay. Bombed it to the bombed it to
bits, firebombed Dresden.
Okay. But the actual winning against
Germany was done by the Soviets, not by
the Americans. The the Soviets defeated
Germany, not the Americans.
Um, yeah. So I I I don't see I I've not
come across any any evidence of this
sort of backhand backdoor deal with
Germany to help the UK fall. No. God
leader says Iran is not ready to give up
its on its uranium. The war is not over
with the use of the mother of all bombs
by the big eagle stone age is possible
is scary. You see Iran will be really
stupid to give up you know one of its
few assets.
If it gives up the option of enriching
uranium and and building nuclear weapons
then it is eventually defenseless
because even if it has a million drones
eventually it will run out of drones.
Right? The only thing that can guarantee
Iran's survival is nuclear weapons.
Iran will be stupid. It will be foolish
to give up that.
And the Americans will say, "As long as
Iran doesn't give that up, we're going
to keep fighting you." So the only thing
that can save Iran is if it tests a
nuclear weapon or two in the coming
days,
right? Long-term survival, that is
required. Short-term survival, I'm sure
Iran can survive short-term and keep
hitting the US and Israel hard.
And
you know, even if Isra even if Iran runs
out of drones and missiles, if the
Americans and Israelis invade, they will
still lose. As Saddam Hussein
discovered, it's impossible to defeat
Iran through land invasion, ground
invasion. It's suicidal. So Iran will
not lose its sovereignty unless there's
a coup from within, which is very
unlikely because of the distributed
nature of the system. The war is not
over, but stone age is likely. It's it's
not likely, but it's possible. Stone age
is possible.
The Americans are perfectly fine
destroying and killing a civilization.
They have no moral qums about this. So
yeah, this war is far from over. This
war is far from over. I agree with you
completely.
Pratep Kumar Roy says Technos J Barat
asks how do East Asian engineers work if
they don't know English? Since most of
the software programming languages and
other global uh technologies like cloud
services AWS etc is in English
they learn that much English. They
learned the Latin alphabet. See this
this alphabet that you see down here.
It's not the English alphabet. It's the
Latin alphabet. Okay? It's not the
English alphabet. It's the Latin
alphabet. So these software engineers,
they will learn the Latin alphabet
without having to learn English. And
they'll learn this the programming
language.
They'll learn that much. So you can do
programming if you are a Chinese
speaking person. You learn that much.
You learn the the the numerals 1 2 3 4 5
in English in the in the that's used in
the English writing system. You learn
this the Latin alphabet.
Then you learn the programming languages
and your managers will communicate
with whoever needs to be communicated
with. So you don't need to learn the
actual English language. Okay. There are
many countries where nobody speaks
English but they use all these things
and they're able to do a great job of
it. Dirj Kamut says Australian Ryan
Williams gave up his Australian
citizenship to play for Indian football
team scored on his debut. We need dual
citizenship for such players. If there
are uh you know athletes and sports
people of Indian origin who are willing
to play for India. Well, we should we
should roll out the red carpet for them.
We should be very grateful. See this guy
Ryan Williams, he gave up his Australian
citizenship, became an Indian Indian
citizen. I think he has Indian ancestry,
right? And he has scored on his debut. I
think we should really really
you know
make him feel welcome in India. Yeah.
And dual citizenship is not possible.
Unfortunately, India can't give dual
citizenship. That will be not possible
because of security reasons and so on.
You can allow dual citizenship only if
you are the most powerful nation in the
world. Otherwise, you can't. So, that
won't work. uh but we should at least
roll out the red carpet for such players
and make them feel very very welcome in
India right and we should not create
problems for them and you know tie them
in tangled
webs of red tape and all that that we do
to our citizens at least that these
people should be exempt from that
manticores we have never used the rights
of propaganda on ourselves we let
western studio stoages win if we want to
propagandize others we start with the
basics of the dark arts on us and then
screw those stooges with it. See, a lot
of this is the fault of the government
of India which simply doesn't care about
playing the propaganda game at all.
Right? I mean, there are so many nations
that play the the propaganda game on
social media that create all these
millions of bot accounts. The Chinese do
that. The Pakistan, even the Pakistanis
with the little poulry money, they do
that. India doesn't do it. Why doesn't
India play this game? Why is the
government of India blind to this? I
don't get it. So, we should do it. I
mean you have Indian citizens fighting a
good fight on Twitter and social media
but that is a disorganized disjointed
effort because each individual does what
he or she feels is right. What you need
is a top-down level concerted effort on
social media across various social media
platforms playing by the same rules that
the other countries play creating bot
accounts and spewing propaganda. You
should do that. I don't know why the
government of India doesn't do it. Maybe
they think it's morally superior not to
do it. I don't know what it is. Maybe
there are practical reasons. I have no
idea. But we should do it. We should.
Pratabsi says, "Tips on one meal per
day. Is it good for health?" It depends.
Our ancestors sometimes they did not eat
for days.
Yeah. Before the agricultural age. See,
our human body, it's evolved over
millions of years. We split from the
chimpanzees about 2 million or so years
ago, right? Our distant cousins, the
chimpanzees, who share 98 something% of
our DNA. Almost the same day. almost the
same DNA. So
historically we have
we have had the kind of lifestyle where
the next meal we had no idea when it was
when it would come. The next meal was
not guaranteed. We were hunter
gatherers.
We would gather what we could eat from
plants and vegetables. We would hunt
what we could what we could hunt and
that was an uncertain way of life. Next
meal was not guaranteed. So you would go
multiple days without food sometimes and
that is what kept you healthy and
strong. Today we eat three meals a day
plus snacks, three and a half, four
meals per day, it's not good for health.
If you eat one meal per day, if you're a
healthy person with no health issues,
you'll be perfectly healthy. So
depending on your activity level, you
will need to ingest a certain amount of
calories per day. For the average
person, it's 2,000 calories. It is said
for some people, depending on how active
they are, it may be 3,000 calories. So
if you can ingest that that amount of
calories with a balanced diet in one
meal, well, you're good to go for the
day. You don't need more food,
right? You can do it over a period of 1
hour if you want or over a period of two
hours if you want or if you are a big
eater, you can do it in one meal. As
long as your full body is functional and
healthy without any issues, you'll be
perfectly fine.
Aris is manticor says even if Iran will
wins the US will still come after us
next. We are soft flesh currently for
them. We need to be prepared for it
anyway and not succumb succumb to it. We
should be prepared for the worst at any
given point in time. We cannot be
complacent.
Why don't we have 3 years worth of
strategic oil reserves or at least one
year worth of strategic oil reserves?
Why is it 84 days or whatever the
government claims? Why
why don't we have strategic gas
reserves? Maybe it's difficult to do
that. At least oil reserve. We should
have at least 365 days. Why don't we
have it? We are complacent. We are
complacent.
We should be prepared for the worst
possible eventuality, including alien
invasions. But forget about alien
invasions. We should be prepared for an
invasion by the most powerful countries
in the world. We hope it never happens,
but if it happens, we should have the
answer to it and we should be able to
win. Which means in the current scenario
we need to have a few million drones and
a few 10 thou 10 20 30 40,000 missiles
of various kinds minimum maybe a 100,000
missiles of various kinds. That's what
how that's how we should prepare. We
should have multiple submarines much
more than what we have. We have to
militarize. We have to be prepared.
Right now we are not prepared at all by
the way to the extent that we should be.
We are prepared to fight Pakistan and
defeat Pakistan. We are prepared to
fight a short war against China. We're
not prepared for a long grinding war of
attrition which could happen. We are not
prepared at all for that. So our
military planners I don't know what
they're doing. And the government I
don't know what it's doing. But these
things we need to forget about what
happened in the past. Let's let bygones
be by. But now we have to quickly adapt
and prepare for any eventuality.
Akshai Janu says why are Europeans not
poor at all? Even small irrelevant Gora
countries still have so much GDP per
capita even better than Japan, China.
What are Goras doing right? Industrial
revolution and the benefit of
colonalization
right they devastated all of the
countries plundered all their wealth
whether it is Africa they completely
devastated Africa took out everything of
value from Africa. Even now there is
neocolonization in Africa which people
don't understand, people don't realize
it's still happening right now. African
nations are being deliberately kept
impoverished and poor
and they did the same to India and and
China to some extent. They devastated
India.
In 1947, India's GDP per cap GDP overall
GDP was less than one less than 2% of
the world's GDP and India's
life expectancy was 30 31 or 32. That's
how badly they destroyed India. They
took they sucked everything of value out
of India
and they have ensured that there is
peace, harmony and good quality of life
in their countries and they they
benefited from the industrial revolution
and all that. So there are multiple
reasons why the Europeans are so wealthy
so wealthy per capita
and why other nations are under it's a
long story but yeah okay developer sai
says Pakistan knew how to betray what
did they get explain your strategy
Pakistan is the the people who run
Pakistan are the generals of the army
shabbah sharif is the puppet
and they are puppets of the US what did
Pakistan get Pakistan got a pat on the
back from the US and the generals got
some cash, some pesa in their bank
accounts in the US or London or wherever
it is. That's what they got. That's what
they got. And the US got to blame Iran
for anything that goes wrong. And maybe
the US wanted us to w his fire, but
Israel didn't want it.
Okay. Mr. Rohit says, "Similar to the
north in the game of thrones, Jud Marwar
kingdom was hostile, brave, loyal, and
men of their words. Why is it not
studied in general history? In India, we
don't talk. We don't say anything good
about Indian kingdoms.
We only exalt
the fake greatness of the Muggal Empire
and the various Turk invaders who ruled
over various parts of India at various
points in time and the Europeans and the
British who devastated India. But we
portray them as great uh liberators and
great colonizers and great uh uh social
reformers.
But Indian kingdoms we don't speak about
them. We don't study that
you are this is the education system is
designed
to produce an inferiority complex in you
and us all of us.
That's what it it's designed to do. It's
designed to keep India feeling inferior
to everybody else. It is done this it
has been done this way by design. Why
don't we teach it? Because the people
who run the education system don't want
you to know these things.
Aries Manticor says the US is heading
towards a soft red blue cultural
divorce. The liberals are driving it.
They are literally being dangerous
criminals destabilizing their own
society demographically. Are they mad?
WTF? I don't know.
Um, it makes no sense to do the kind of
things that they do. It makes no sense
for them to allow children to to be
physically mutilated irreparably.
A lot of the things they do make no
sense in any civilized society, but they
do it.
The the
the reds are the Republicans, the blues
are the Democrats. The blues four years
that that Biden was the puppet head of
the government, they had opened the
southern border, the Mexican border.
They were allowing all kinds of
dangerous people, undocumented, illegal
immigrants to enter the country.
And the deal was that they have to vote
Democrat. So they were treating these
people as as as a vote bank. The same
way that various Indian politicians,
various parts of India treat Bangladesh
as is a vote bank, captive vote bank.
Then this is crazy. It's stupid. It's
very bad for the country. But that's
what politicians do for their own
personal gain.
Cryptochimp says clear signs of an
internal rift in Iran. Reformist lobby
around Pesh, Kan, Zarif, and Rouhani
pushing soft coup. They push for
negotiations and issue threats on X
instead of retaliating Lebanon massacre.
Looks like that. Looks like that. Yeah.
Well, the IRGC needs to um look into
this matter, I would say. And if certain
people like Pzashki, Zarif Rouhani are
allegedly hypothetically
doing something that's not good for the
country which will eventually lead to
the country's fall. Well then, you know,
if that's a soft coup, then you can do a
counter coup against that. But it looks
like what you are saying is, yeah, it's
interesting that somebody said this on
this live stream. Pesashka and Zarif and
Rouani are pushing for negotiations
when negotiations are not going to solve
any of finance problems.
Only a clear victory is going to ensure
Iran's survival. Negotiations
are going to lead you down the road
towards disaster if you are Iran.
So I agree with you. Yeah, I agree.
Okay. Akshai Janu says even when poor
the west
even when poor was Iran still
sophisticated unlike us? I don't know
what is the meaning of sophisticated.
Can you define sophisticated?
In what way was Iran sophisticated?
Iran has a higher GDP per capita than
India. By the way, even today, despite
all the sanctions and despite all the
horrors that the West have
imposed on Iran, Iran still has a higher
GDP per capita than India. Let's let's
quickly check it out.
What are India and Iran's GDP per capita
today?
So Iran's GDP per GDP per capita India's
GDP per capita is $3,51 today.
Iran's GDP per capita is 3,897. It's
higher than India. It's 33 3897 to 5190
significantly
higher than India if it is 5190. Okay.
So in Iran is per capita richer than
India first of all. Secondly, Iran has a
far better education system than India.
If it offends some of you, deal with it.
Facts don't care about your feelings.
India, Iran's education system is far
superior to India's education system.
First of all, there is no reservations
there. It is merit-based.
And secondly,
education in Iran, Iran is free for all
even at the university level. There are
private institutions also but you have
universities at the highest level with
the highest uh level of sc technological
education that is free for people who
the best of the best can get free
education and healthcare is free I mean
if you need heart surgery or something
you may have to pay for it but basic
healthcare is free so overall Iran has a
much better system than India there's
far less allegedly corruption in Iran
right okay
abai parasar says I'm not able to buy
the history course. It keeps telling me
payment gate authorized. I was trying to
pay by G GPA. Can I still buy it? I will
have to look into it. I have not seen
that platform for a while. Uh and if the
platform is not working, I'll have to
transfer this to a different platform. I
suppose I'll have to look into this.
Okay. So, I'll look into it. Thank you
for the for letting me know uh what you
had uh experienced about this. I'll look
into it. There is manticores. I did a
thought experiment. Maybe the reason we
haven't why we haven't found a theory of
everything is because we haven't leaned
into our acoustic and vibration senses.
Maybe we need to try to understand
physics from that side not from that
side non- light. See acoustic and
vibration senses are also
electromagnetic in nature.
Light is electromagnetic.
Sound
is also at the fundamental level
electromagnetic.
Okay.
Vibrations.
Vibrations. Well, sound is vibration.
It is the vibration of atoms
and molecules.
And atoms and molecules
they do feel and they do operate by the
electromagnetic force. Right? So once
again you have at the fundamental level
electromagnetism being involved in the
matter.
We have to
I agree that we have to understand
physics from the nonlight side
which means non- electromagnetic side.
See electromagnetism also involves a
weak force the electroeak force.
So which is the force that we need to
understand better? it the the force that
doesn't involve electromagnetism or
light which is gravity. We don't
understand gravity and that's the
problem. We don't understand gravity at
all. I mean we have the best theory so
far is general relativity but that
theory isn't it is flawed. We know that
very well. It's flawed. It throws up
infinities. It flow it throws up
singularities. It doesn't work with
quantum mechanics. You can't mix the two
together. There is there are flaws in
general relativity and unless we address
that we won't we won't get a theory or
we won't get progress towards a theory
of everything. So the issue is it's
gravity we don't understand gravity
that's the issue.
Okay next question
Modi G recently announced reservation of
women in legislative bodies. My views I
am all for Nar Shaki. We should have
more reservations everywhere. I think we
should have 300% reservations everywhere
maybe 500%. should go against nature. I
mean you can't have anything beyond 100%
but we should go beyond 100%. What can I
say? My views I am against reservation
of any kind.
Ericson says the US will use EMPs
against Chinese drones. They won't use
it against Iran. Also if it wasn't for
straight formos Iran would have been
flattened by now. Okay sir, if you say
so.
EMPs
electromagnetic pulses against Chinese
drones. Well, to use EMPs, you need to
do something very nasty. What is what is
an EMP? It's an electromagnetic pulse.
How do you generate a massive enough
electromagnetic magnetic pulse to
destroy well to cause significant
damage? You have to detonate a nuke.
Without detonating a nuke, can you
generate a significant electromagnetic
pulse? Very hard to do that.
Um, if it wasn't for the straight of
hormones, Iran would have been flattened
by now.
I don't understand the logic. Iran is
strangling the choke the is it's
strangling the state of Hormuz, right?
So why doesn't the US if it is capable
of threatening Iran, why doesn't it
flatten Iran? That will end the strangle
hold on the state of Hormuz.
If the US can flatten Iran and Iran is
strangling the straight of Hormuz, then
why doesn't the US go and solve the
problem by flattening Iran? The problem
is the US can't flatten Iran. And even
if they flatten Iran and use 10 nukes,
Iran will still keep fighting. That is
the problem. And Iran will still be able
to strangle the the state of Hormuz. So
yeah, the US the problem isn't that the
US can't threaten Iran. The problem is
that the US can't open the state of
Hormos. Okay. And the state of Hormos is
not some kind of fragile thing that has
to be kept intact. It's it's a natural
geographic position location formation.
Okay. Um Jagada says BB tweeted pause on
attack on Lebanon. Looks like Pakistan
will get media to clean up from
terrorist nation to peacemaker. We'll
see about that. Has Netanyahu tweeted
something? Let me take a look. Um yum
yum yum.
Okay. Let us see Netanyahu Twitter.
Shall we see? Give me a second.
Okay. Uh you know what? I'll not go and
research this right now. I will look
into it later. But if in case in case
Netanyahu is pausing the attack on
Lebanon, then maybe the ceasefire could
become viable,
then we'll see about it. I don't care
about Pakistan's image, whether it is
rehabilitated, whether it goes to hell.
I don't care. Pakistan is not important
for us. Please keep your eyes on the
ball. What is important for India is
India keeps going forward in the right
direction. If Pakistan's image is built
up artificially, I don't care. It is not
going to make life better in Pakistan.
We have to make life better in India. We
want to make India a great nation, a
great power. Pakistan's image being
artificially
uh you know
artificially artificially glorified or
whatever it's not going to make Pakistan
a great nation in in the real sense
right so please forget about all these
things about about cosmetic appearances
let's let's focus on the substance
substantive matters which is the actual
growth and progress of a country
manticor says the whole ceasefire farce
was engineered by the US to lower the
domestic pressure and shift blame to
Israel, Pakistan, Iran in an attempt to
save midterms and try to fool Iran into
giving them more time. Yeah, I agree. I
agree. I agree. Pakistan was simply a
willing tool, a willing accomplice for
the US. They are happy to be the fall
guy for this as long as the generals get
money in their pocket every time.
That's all it is for the Pakistani
generals. They don't care about the
nation whether it is its image is is is
tarnished as a consequence of their
actions or whatever. Right? this whole
thing see there are two possibilities
either Pakistan has its own agenda and
it betrayed the US and Israel and and
Iran at the same time but if it betrays
the US Pakistan won't survive so the
second scenario is way more likely that
Pakistan simply acted at the behest of
the US and did all this you know the
whole ceasefire farce and the
backstabbing of Iran
um so this gives the US the opportunity
to blame others they can blame Pakistan
they can blame Iran they can blame
Israel also if required. They won't
blame Israel ever, but they can blame
Pakistan in Iran for the whole debacle
and this can also fool Iran into giving
the Americans more time. So you have a
couple of days where the ceasefire
doesn't hold then you again bring the
ceasefire back into operation and then
say another two weeks and the US is
bringing in more troops, more
reinforcements, more supplies all the
time. They're not they've not stopped
that. The US clearly is waiting for the
right time to start the war again and go
in for the kill against Iran and Iran
would be stupid to fall for this stupid
for for this farce. For some reason
Pzashia and other Iranian leaders are
willing to negotiate and and pause the
whole matter. So maybe there is some
hidden weakness of theirs or maybe they
are I don't know. Yeah, doesn't make
sense. Iran doesn't benefit from a
ceasefire. The US benefits from a
ceasefire. Israel benefits from a
ceasefire. Iran does not. So I don't
know why they are going for a ceasefire.
Okay. Arismantic course says the Manipur
issue is mostly hubris by the government
as they negotiated by with similar
militants in other parts of the eastern
bat. They don't get the fact that
Manipur issue is fundamentally
different. What can I say? The
government has its own experts. Right?
The government of India has certain
domain experts who are allegedly experts
in northeast India. Experts on northeast
India. Experts on Manipur. I am a
Manipur expert. I will now go and
give the give the government of India at
various levels advice about Manipur.
What is the right strategy? What is the
right policy we have to adopt in
Manipur?
And then when everything goes to hell, I
will now stop saying I'm a manipur
expert. I'll go and do something else.
So um the problem is in India, we don't
understand our far east. It's too
complicated for us. We don't care about
the far east.
those people there who who cares what
happens to them.
It it's it's sad what is being done to
uh to Manipur especially Manipur is an
ongoing disaster.
Arismantic says it's not that we don't
have ambition the it's the fact that the
government is ignored ISRO and let it
get infiltrated by traitors. Okay. Only
saving grace is that NSA seems to have
finally woken up. Very shameful. Okay. I
am not aware of ISRO being infiltrated
allegedly by traitors. I'm not aware of
this at all. Okay. But yeah, ISRO has
been ignored. ISRO doesn't get enough
funding. If it gets a little bit of
funding and if the projects are done
with less funding, you to return the
money to the government and no major
projects are approved. No ambitious
projects are approved.
We have these little rockets PSLV, GSLV,
which we say are the most powerful
rockets compared to what this the
Americans have. These are little
rockets, little little.
And now even the PSLV has failed a
couple of times. Maybe it's sabotage.
So uh
if you ignore ISRO, it means you have no
ambition for ISRO. If the government of
India is ignoring ISRO for years, it
means the government of India doesn't
consider the space program to be
important. Which means the government of
India doesn't have any ambition for
India and space.
What?
So disappointing. I I I hope that we
have woken up now. I don't know about
the NSA what he is doing, what he's not
doing. I don't I have no idea. But if he
has woken up, if we have woken up, well,
I'm glad in that case. Yeah. But
overall, the way we have completely
neglected our space program is super
disappointing.
Super disappointing.
It's like we have no understanding of
where the future lies.
Anik is a new member. Thank you very
much. Anukit and Vanit and welcome to
the channel's membership. Thank you.
Udai Kumar says US Congress confirming
aliens. Grouch credible. I don't know
who Grouch is. US Congress confirming
aliens. Show me the evidence and I'll
believe you.
If they say put out a statement that we
have met aliens, I don't believe it. I
want to see actual hard incontrovertible
evidence. I don't care what somebody's
opinions or claims are. Whether it is a
so-called conspiracy theorist or a
so-called American senator, if they make
claims without any evidence, I will not
take it seriously at all. Credibility is
built on evidence. I don't know who Gush
is, but is if Gush makes a claim without
producing evidence that substantiate
substantiates it, then that person is
not credible. As simple as that. If the
US government puts out a statement and
puts this stamp of approval of the US
government, it doesn't mean it becomes
automatically credible. You need hard
incontrovertible evidence for
credibility and that is missing thus
far.
Hershan says what what according to you
would be an ideal approach moving
forward for the fighter jet program of
India? Could the GE engine be replaced
and replaced with 10 years R&D?
What's the ideal approach? ideal
approach. If the French are being
difficult, dump the Rafal.
Buy the Russian Zuko 57.
As long as they're giving you full
technology, full manufacturing in India,
not assembly, but full manufacturing in
India and full access to source codes.
Pay them whatever it takes. It will be
cheaper than the Rafal for sure per
piece. And you will be able to integrate
all the Indian weapon systems with the
Suka 57 instead of the Rafal. So take if
this French are being very very very
very difficult then dump the Rafal get
the Suka 57 number one. Secondly keep
developing the AMCA the advanced medium
combat aircraft of India. Keep
developing it.
go ahead with the u with the partnership
with Safon with the which is the French
uh jet engine manufacturer and
co-develop jointly develop a jet engine
with the French as long as you get full
u you know control over the over the
technology it becomes indigenous
technology and at the same time don't
kill the cowry project keep developing
it pour in sufficient money in the
cavary project and make it eventually
viable for the AMCA,
right? That's what we would do. It's a
long-term thing in 10, 20 years.
In the meanwhile, India should go all in
on drones and ballistic missiles and
cruise missiles.
So that way, if we have a few million
drones and maybe 100,000 different kinds
of missiles, then it doesn't matter if
our air force has is short of the
sufficient number of squadrons. Anyway,
long-term air force is not going to
matter. It's going to be all robotics.
It's going to be all unmanned combat
very vehicles, unmanned aircraft and
drones and missiles. That's that is the
future.
Fighter planes with humans inside are
increasingly going the way of the
dinosaurs. It's already apparent now. So
is India should go ahead with this
program in my opinion.
Krishant Bordoy says watch the move
watch the movie in a houseful houseful
hall. It's more amazing. I always prefer
to be in a peaceful place with no crowd
around me who's shouting and screaming
and passing comments. I don't like that.
I like to be genuinely immersed in a
movie.
I have been in situations where I've had
a whole bunch of people around me and
you typically have people just
commenting and chattering and talking
and shouting and clapping and hooting
and and raising slogans that distracts
you from what's happening in the movie.
I like to be genuinely immersed in a
movie. So that's how I prefer to watch
movies. I like to prefer watch movies in
while being immersed in that world, not
while being distracted by all the
monkeying around around you. So that's
why I would prefer to watch it in a in a
hall there where there's less people.
Pratep Kumar Roy says AI says the antim
antimatter transport experiment was
carried out at CERN near Geneva, France.
I know friends. Uh inside CERN's
antiproon decelerator complex they
trapped it using magnetic containment
system. Okay, let's see. Antimatter
transport experiment.
Let's see.
Antimatter transport experiment. CERN
base experiment. Uh CERN succeeds in
transporting something or the other. Do
you have the CERN career here? Okay,
it's been transported. Okay, that's
interesting. Okay, maybe I should have
um reject. Okay. So, nature says 24th of
March 2026, antimatter has been
transported for the first time ever in
the back of sun's truck. Okay. Okay.
You're transporting antimatter. Okay. Uh
so they have succeeded in doing all
that. So, okay. Before I even read this,
let me tell you antimatter
is the most ephemeral volatile substance
ever because it consists of
antiparticles.
See what are the what are the particles
that we have? You have protons,
neutrons, electrons, right? That these
are the particles that make up our
atoms. Protons, neutrons, electrons. So
antimatter is matter in which the
particles have the opposite quantum
numbers, opposite charge, opposite
everything.
So an antiro so protons are positively
charged particles. Antirotons will have
the same mass but the opposite charge.
So antirotons are have the same mass as
a proton but the opposite charge
negative charge. Anti-electrons or
posetrons have the same mass as a as an
electron but a positive charge. And
anti-utrons
are not neutrons. They have opposite
quantum numbers. Okay. So antimatter if
it comes into contact with regular
matter it immediately
disintegrates. It it just gives off pure
energy. It's an explosion. Pure energy
is is released as a consequence.
And that's why if you have antimatter,
if it comes into contact with air, it
will explode.
If it comes into contact with the glass
of your container, it will explode. So
antimatter has to be kept in vacuum,
complete pure vacuum. And it can't be
allowed to even touch the walls of your
container, which is why you need
magnetic confinement.
That's why it's so difficult to
transport antimatter. So difficult. So
now let's read. With that understood,
let's read this. So, physicists have
succeeded in transporting for the first
time this thing antimatter
da.
So the so
92 antirotons were transported in a in a
specially designed bottle that traps the
particle using magnetic fields, magnetic
confinement. Once again, like I said,
the bottle traveled at the back of a
truck, taking a 30-minute journey around
the lab's site.
So essentially you want to take the
antiparticles to a location free of
experimental noise where antiprotons can
be studied with greater precision then
it's possible in discern antimatter
factory where they are produced. So it
is the only place in the world that
produces usable quantities of
antiprotons.
Uh okay okay okay so that's the thing
that's the thing they transported
antimatter and the antimatter was
confined in a container using magnetic
confinement and it was put into a back
of a truck it was moved around for 30
minutes. That was the thing.
Interesting. Okay. Nice. Nice. Good to
hear. And thank you for letting me know
about this. Thank you, Pratip. Thank
you. Amandiari says, "Why Palestine land
given to Israel and no compensation for
them?
Might is right."
And historically the the Jewish people,
it was their homeland also, right? It
was of course historically the homeland
of the Jewish people this region which
is called by some people as Palestine.
Right? So so 2,000 years ago the Jews
lived there and then they were expelled
from there by because of various
reasons. the Romans had a hand had a
part to role to play in this and so on
historical reasons for this and that's
why the the Jewish people were wandering
around around the world and then then in
the early 20th century they decided to
reoccupy the place to return to their
homeland and they found Arabs living
there so the Arabs also were living for
a while and then the Jews returned and
said this is our land so who's wrong
who's right there's no wrong there's no
right so whoever has the might has the
right and that's what
And whoever is the might is under no
obligation to give any compensation
unfortunately.
Jagada says India key problems. One poor
education policy. Second northeast
issued disaster. Third it job disaster.
Fourth infiltration and demographics
issues. Fourth army flaws jets subs
Navik. Sixth no leadership. Seven
language war. Eight civic sense. Nine
dual poly in key sectors. 10 Babu
minister families in US EU EU. Agree.
Rank it.
Um I don't know what the duopoly in key
sectors is. Apart from that I understand
everything else. Uh what are the worst
issues?
The root cause of so many issues is the
is the disastrous education system of
India. Trash garbage. Utterly utterly
garbage. New education policy is is
nothing. It's going to solve no problem.
No issues. Uh so there is that. Yeah. Uh
the education system is the root cause
of most of India's problems. Secondly,
infiltration in demographics. Big big
big problem. Completely agree with you.
Huge problem for India. I don't know why
we not doing anything about this.
Thirdly, uh leadership. I'm not saying
Prime Minister Modi is a bad leader. I'm
saying overall if you look at all the
leaders leadership positions in various
parts of the country at various levels,
overall overall there are some
exceptions who are brilliant, some
brilliant leaders, but overall super
mediocre or less than mediocre. Um
next um you know jets, subs, Navic is a
big issue of course. Yeah. And the 20th
century mindset that many of our
military planners seem to have that's a
big issue. Uh the import lobby is a big
issue. The lack of indigenous
manufacturing of weapons in India is a
big issue. Right? Uh language war is a
big issue. We need to have a common
civilizational language that needs to be
reimposed in India which is Suskrit. But
no no no no Sanskrit imposition. Right?
So language war um
um northeast issue is a big issue right
completely agree with that. So I don't
know exactly how to rank it but I
completely agree with pretty much
everything you say. I'm not sure what
the dual poly in key sectors is but it's
obviously an issue you know baboos
bureaucrats ministers etc having
families settled in the US in the EU
with citizenship there and why are you
here
your future is there your family's
future is there why why are you here so
that's an issue
all these things are issues I don't know
definitely I would say education system
number one long-term but most urgent is
the illegal infiltration of god knows
how Tens of millions of Bangladeshes in
India and cookies and Pakistanis and
Rohhingyas and God knows what else. Why
that is the most pressing and immediate
issue and all the other issues are
ranked in various rankings I suppose.
Yeah. Overall I agree with
essentially almost everything you say
apart from the dual polinctors. I'm not
sure what you mean by that. I have not
studied that.
Okay,
Katos Artasi says, "Tajix declared
official state ideology as Arianism
arguing for ancient continuity using
archaeology in Avesta while still while
we still spout Arian invasion theory."
Really? Let me let me see once again
about this
2006 Tajakistan Arianism.
Sir, the government of Rajasthan in 2006
under President Imam Al Mali Rahman
declared the year of Arian civilization.
This was an official state initiative
focused on celebrating and studying the
ancient heritage of the Tajik people
with a strong emphasis on connecting
modern Tajic national identity with
ancient Arian
roots which is Iranian Zoroastan roots.
The initiative was not related to the
early Christian heresy. Okay. Um
so it's a socopolitical secularized
national identity project often referred
to as the Arian myth or Arian
civilization project and so on.
Uh the government promoted the idea that
Arian civilization marked the beginning
of history for the thic nation.
Um
okay okay what else? Uh Arian symbols.
Okay. So okay okay okay I will look into
this looks interesting and the Tajik
seem to have a certain amount of
self-respect at least
okay aniket says small correction no one
gives source code Russia did not give
source code for soy 30 nor will they for
soy 57 but France can give access to
weapons integration like Russia
I think Russia will be even willing to
give source code no one gives source
code the Americans have given source
code to Israel by the way for the F-35
Israel can do whatever it wants with the
F-35.
Okay.
Um, and if you're paying a tremendous
amount of money, you want the source
code.
You want it.
And if the Russians are also not giving
the source code for Suka 57, don't buy
it. Don't buy it. Just produce more
of whatever you can.
So India should insist on the source
code. You see you can also say that
nobody shares nuclear technology right
nobody will share nuclear reactor
technology
nobody will but Russia has shared that
with India India's nuclear submarines
they have miniaturized nuclear reactors
who helped India with that technology
Russia did.
Does anybody give nuclear submarines to
anyone? Russia gives to India. India and
Russia have that amount of trust.
Russia will give the Sukoy 57 source
code to India provided we give them a
fair price.
Okay, please be aware of this also.
Generally, I agree with you that source
code generally nobody gives that. But
India and Russia have a different
relationship than what happens at the
general level. Okay? It's a special
relationship.
So as long as see source code is is
obviously a prized asset. It's developed
by your specialists over years
and it's built on top of the source code
for the RUK30 that also took years. So
it's it's a very valuable thing and you
don't give it to most nations but for
India they will make an exception as
long as India pays a pays a fair fair
price for it. So I would say yes.
Jakar says stealth solutions especially
it is finished Baba.
It is finished.
Why is it finished? Artificial
intelligence models are getting better
and better. Right now the models that
you have
they still need human supervision. Okay.
but allegedly anthropic mythos allegedly
is almost AGI
and they don't even releasing it
allegedly to the public. Maybe it's a
maybe it's a publicity stunt. Maybe it's
a marketing stunt. Maybe it's real.
Eventually, let's say in 3 years time,
you will have
AI models that will essentially do the
job of multiple
um med middle level programmers
at the same super fast.
So, the real skill that you will need is
how to handle teams of AI agents. The
solution, there's no solution. This is
the new reality of the world.
So only senior developers will be
valuable. Senior developers, senior
programming programmers and engineers
that will be valuable solution. India
has to develop its own
sovereign AI systems that are on par
with the best system in the world. Today
you have opensource systems that are
almost as good as the the current
anthropic models. Open-source systems
that you can install in your local
machines and run privately.
open source open weight systems you have
India has to become an AI power that's
the only solution
and uh yeah overall AI will take lots of
jobs that that's going to happen
aon says education system would take 20
years to improve if we start today
minimum 20 years which would not affect
the current government regime but then
why not improve education because
politicians are in this game for the
long run.
Politicians are in the game for the long
run.
They care about today, but they also
care about 20 years from now. Let's say
you're a 50-y year politician. You you
you're a politician, you're 50 years
old. 50 years old means you are a
reasonably young politician. At the age
of 50, you are reasonably young in
politics. And as a politician, you will
want to be ruling until your mid 80s.
In 20 years when you are 70 if the
education system has come created a
whole breed of young people who think
very differently from you and who you
can't fool then you will not want this
to happen and let's say you are from a
political family which means you want
your son and your daughters to also
become politicians and rule over the
Indians then why will you want the
system to change why
do other countries fear not fear educ
educated population how did they manage
to educate the Iranians don't seem to
fear an educated population their
education system is far better than
India's
The US did not fear fear an educated
population in the 1950s. They had the
world's best education system in the
1950s. Then they dumbed it down. The
Americans today fear an educated
population. Today they do. That's why
they have dumbed their education system
down today.
If you see the let's say
seven standard mathematics
exam questions from the 1950s and you
compare that with today's seven standard
mathematics exam questions today the
standards have declined very drastically
in the US.
So the US does fear an educated
population. The the Iranians don't. The
Chinese don't. The Indians very much do.
Pratitumar Roy says, "Space episode
request. Good night, sir.
I could make videos about space
possibly. Space episode. I think
there'll be like 50 people watching
maximum."
Uh anyway, maybe I'll do it. I've done
in the past, so maybe I can do this sort
of thing once in a while. Thank you so
much for the recommendation and thank
you for the questions and everything.
Good night, sir. Good night to you.
Divodas Putra says, "Persians finding
Indian cousins on X. I'll go tuning."
No, that's happened out of the blue.
Just happened. Wasn't expected. Wasn't
supposed to be that way. But yes,
Persians and Indians are suddenly
finding common cause on Twitter. It's
good to see India and Persia started
drifting apart after the Rashidun
Caulifhate's invasion and occupation of
Persia and the imposition of the foreign
religion. And ever since India and
Persia have slowly gradually drifted
apart now we are somehow we seem to be
you know Indian and Persian jenzi seem
to be fighting finding each other now
and it's good if India and Persia the
people come together we seem to have
inhabited very different spheres of
existence until now yeah but now it
looks like India and Persia may the
people may once again start discovering
each other which will be great I'll be
happy if that happens So good overall. I
don't think it's algorithm tuding. Maybe
the algorithm will change now to to
prevent this from happening. But right
now Indians and Persians are liking each
other's posts and tweets and whatnot and
talking to each other. Fantastic. I'm
glad to see that. Ghoulibar says BB stop
after call with Leberan PM. Indian e
effort to isolate Pakistan is a
diplomatic fail. I know war is bad in
India benefits from peace but want talk
to fail.
India is not doing any efforts to
isolate Pakistan. As long as the
Americans have Pakistan in their pocket,
India can't isolate Pakistan. India's
only job is to stay out of the war and
ensure that the war doesn't have too
much of a fallout effect on India.
India's policy towards Pakistan is of
ignoring Pakistan and not dealing with
Pakistan, not bringing Pakistan to the
table. You can't do a thing about what
the US does with Pakistan. As long as
the US finds Pakistan valuable, Pakistan
will not be isolated. India is not
making any efforts to isolate Pakistan.
Okay? If you imagine so then you are
imagining wrong.
Maybe your news anchors are saying India
is trying to isolate Pakistan. Maybe
your favorite YouTubers are saying that
India is trying to isolate Pakistan. I
have never said that.
So because of this fake image that's
this fake narrative that your Indian
YouTubers and media have created of
India trying to isolate Pakistan maybe
that's why you believe that India has
been trying to isolate Pakistan India is
failing India is not trying that at all
the government of India has a very clear
policy we ignore Pakistan we're not
trying to isolate them is your your
great news anchors
they are the ones who have created this
narrative
All right, please understand that the
government of India has never tried to
isolate Pakistan. We have simply refused
to engage with them which is the right
policy.
Um BB stop with call with Labor and PM.
Okay, that's that's breaking news. It
looks like I am not seeing the news
right now so I don't know but okay,
we'll we'll we'll see what happens. Um
okay. All right.
Akshai Janu says, "Will we reach $15
trillion GDP? What do you think?"
Someday we will. Someday we will.
Yeah, someday we will.
When? I have no idea. Vir Kamat says,
"Sorry, but glorified autocomplete can
never be AGI." Well, we haven't seen
mythos, so I don't know. I'm saying it
is alleged. Allegedly. So in your
opinion, you think that all AI systems
are chat bots and they are simply
autocompletes.
Don't be so sure about that.
Okay, there are certain AI systems that
have made advances in mathematics that
have not happened in decades. Maybe you
are not aware of that. That is new
information being created, not not
autocomplete at all.
That's breaking barriers that have
existed in mathematics for a very long
time. Pure mathematics.
Okay.
AI is creating actual new information.
It's not just autocomplete.
Most of it, you know, the vast majority
of people the way they use AI is they
use it as an autocomplete mechanism as a
chatbot.
Don't be like the vast majority of
people. There are ways of using AI in
which are completely novel ways. You're
you're going into novel directions
definitely not not autocomplete
and and you have different tiers of AI,
right? You have the um extended effort
AI models and and deep thinking AI
models and then you have the fast AI
models and so on. Those are autocomplete
models. But there are AI models that are
not autocomplete that take time to think
and they give you depending on how you
handle them. They can give you really
surprising results.
Right? So it's not all autocomplete.
It's not all autocomplete. Don't be so
complacent about this matter sir. Don't
be so complacent and don't be so sure
about this being autocomplete.
Okay. Mayor says Mayor Goar says how did
we fail important project like Nav'i? So
many satellite failure. We should have
been we should have been superpowered in
satellite technology by now.
We should see how many space launches
does India do per year. Five six rockets
we launch.
How many does SpaceX launch in a year?
150 200.
Let's see. Let's see
how many rockets did India launch per
year from 2023 until 2025.
So 2023 seven launches 2024 five
launches 2025 five launches 755 Now
let's see Space X okay India 755 Space X
it's a private company SpaceX
India 755 SpaceX 98 138 165 Do you see
the scale
So India simply has no ambition.
Space X is you can't even compare India
space program with SpaceX. SpaceX is a
behemoth. India is a tiny little
mosquito compared to that.
Five launches per year. Are we even a
serious country?
Right. And our rockets are measly little
rockets compared to what SpaceX and NASA
has.
Yeah. Payload to to low earth orbit is
what a few tons, three, four tons, five
tons, whatever it is. H zero ambition.
Zero ambition. And this Navic thing, we
knew that each Navic satellite will last
maximum 10 years. So we could have
started planning 10 years ago. We should
have had backup plans in case rockets
fail, satellites fail, whatever fails.
We should have had backup plans. We
should have developed our own atomic
clocks in case foreign clocks are
failing. This is simply
I don't know what to say. So
stupid failure.
Stupid failure. We we we could have seen
this coming 10 years ago and we let we
let this happen. This is a failure by
the government of India. There is no
other way to put it.
Aka Janu says in Japan I saw Sarasati
Ashokand Shakuni ditarashtra and old
temples your tip on this part of
festival Japan about influence. I've
been speaking about this for years.
Saraspati
is called Benzan in Japan. Ben Zaiton.
Okay.
She is regarded as a Buddhist goddess,
but she's not. See, Benzon. Um, Japan.
Benon.
Oh, come on. Benon.
Benthon. Okay.
This is the same goddess. Instead of the
Vina, she has a Japanese instrument,
right?
Same goddessi
benzan. Then we have kangitan. Who is
kangitan? It is shrianh binayakan.
Kangin.
It is Shri Ganesh, right? Japan, India.
So we have all the Hindu gods and
goddesses who are part of the Buddhist
and Shinto pantheon of gods in Japan. We
also have the to Japanese to which are
just like the Ashokas Tamba, right?
Tori gates. Look at this. This is
obviously modeled after the ancient
Indian gates that we we had during the
Morian era, right?
So, Japan's culture is founded on a
bedrock of Indian culture and the
connections go back almost 2,000 years.
And this is something I've been speaking
about for years. But now thankfully uh
more and more people are beginning to
realize this not just because of me but
because you travel to Japan and if you
have the eyes and if you your eyes are
open you will begin to notice things
right so yeah it's it's a very deep
connection between India and Japan you
have Shinto rituals in Japan in temples
which are essentially fire rituals which
are and and the chanting is Vic Sanskrit
chanting they still chant in Sanskrit
and they use the the I think the not the
shardas script but the siddhum script in
Japan.
So there are all these deep connections
between India and Japan and we should
explore this more.
So our culture is essentially the same
but it manifests itself in very
different shapes and forms but still the
foundations are the same. India and
Japan honest human says always loved
your style of working and and been
implementing in my life. Please don't
mind this quick question. How to make
yourself thick skin. Thank you.
How do you make yourself Well, first of
all, thank you very much. Thank you very
much. How do you make yourself thick
skinned? I have no idea. Um, it's not
like I used to be thin skinned and then
I developed techniques to make myself
thick skinned. I was just born this way.
I simply don't care what anyone says.
You please, you say nice things about
me, I will say thank you. It doesn't go
to my head and become make me egoistic.
So if somebody praises me, I'm grateful.
I'm thankful. I I I will thank you. But
I it will not, you know, secretly make
me feel great. Ah, everyone's praising
me. I don't care. And if people say
nasty things about me, once again, it
makes no difference to me. It makes no
difference. I know who I am. I know my
flaws. I know my deficiencies. I know my
strengths and strong points and all
that. I know exactly who I am. And what
somebody says makes no difference to me
whatsoever. I simply don't care.
Okay. So, how do you develop a thick
skin? I think the way to develop a thick
skin is by thick skin is by genuinely
understand who you are truly who you
are. Who who are you as a person?
What are your characteristics?
What are your strengths? What are your
weaknesses? What are your likes? What
are your dislikes? Why are you here? Why
have you been put in this world?
If you truly understand yourself then
you will not need any inputs from
anybody else and if somebody passes
judgment or whatever you'll essentially
feel like laughing okay you think so
good for you so I think the way to
develop a thick skin is by truly truly
spending the time which takes maybe
weeks or months maybe even years to
genuinely understand who tr you truly
are deep inside. Most of us human beings
never take the time to understand who we
are. Most human beings live their entire
lives without truly knowing who they
are.
Yeah. You just absorb thoughts and and
and and ideologies and all stuff from
other people and the language you use is
recycled language used by others. But
what is your actual standard of the
world? You don't even know what it is.
So that don't be that person. If you are
like that, you will always be uh you'll
you'll then naturally and automatically
be thin skinned,
right? If you truly know understand who
you are, you won't give a damn what
anyone says. So understand who you are.
I think that is the true way to to
develop a thick skin because then other
people's opinions don't matter will not
matter to you. All right, sir. Uh all
the best.
Pad Manabhar says Hindu temples should
be run by devotees and not by government
servants. I completely agree with that.
The government if it is a secular
government has no business interfering
in the affairs of Hindu temples when it
doesn't interfere in the affairs of the
religious uh um structures of other
other uh non-Indian religions.
The government of India should has no
business running Hindu temples. This
needs to change. I completely agree with
you. Krishnant Bordaloy says, "No,
people were immersed like there was some
hooting, but when the movie was over,
they were all emotional and traffic. It
was amazing. See all the post post
credits." Okay. I'm glad you had a great
experience. I'm glad you I'm glad you
enjoyed it with with everyone together.
Awesome. Awesome. Jagara says, "Deopoly
Telecom, airline, economy, etc. Who is
Bijnak? What the relation with the CI or
false?" I have no idea. I have no idea
about these matters.
Uh teleony telephone telecom airlines
new poly oh you mean there are in in in
the airlines there are two major players
oh that way okay e-commerce etc
uh I don't know about bijop relationship
with CI or not I have no idea whatsoever
I will not even discuss that because
first of all I don't know and yeah okay
so I understand what you mean by police
you you should you should neither have
monopolies nor do police the US is is a
poly Republicans and Democrats, that
sort of thing. Okay, I get it. I get it.
Yeah, that also is an issue. We should
have multiple players in a fair playing
field, level playing field. I agree with
you. Okay, and I think that brings me to
the end of today's questions. Thank you
so much everybody for the questions.
Really appreciate the time you spend
with me, the questions you asked me. So,
I'll end this here. Thank you so much
everyone. Keep raising your standards,
keep asking questions, keep learning and
I'll see you this Saturday evening India
time. Until then, take care and see you
soon. Bye for now.